<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spain on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/spain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spain on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/spain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 95 to 98 September 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-95&#34;&gt;Day 95&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-95&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day it was sunny but cold. I rode for about 10 miles South from Tende on the D6204 and then took the D2204 to go over the Coll De Brouis. The road was fantastic and the views were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/01-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engine Rebuild and Spain December 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The damage to the bike engine was substantial so I knew that it would take more than a few days to fix it. As I have owned and ridden bikes continually since I was a teenager my acquired mechanical knowledge and abilities allow me to do all of my own bike maintenance. Fortunately these skills and knowledge also allow me to undertake major mechanical tasks such as the engine repair. The engine removal was straightforward enough and once out the rest of the bike was very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/01-rb.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 August 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:49:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-28&#34;&gt;Day 28&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends is always good but leaves a sour taste when it comes time to say goodbye. This occasion was no different. So after a few days rest and relaxation I headed North on the C14 from Reus and made for the Pyrenees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/01-28.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 24 to 27 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:55:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-24&#34;&gt;Day 24&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After saying my goodbyes to my friends in Alvor I headed West. Riding along the N125 I passed by Faro and continued untill I had to join the motorway to cross the border in to Spain. I then continued on the A49 from the border, circumventing Seville and headed South on the N4 and A381 till I eventually reached Gibraltar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/01-24.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 20 to 23 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-20&#34;&gt;Day 20&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well with the best of intentions I arrived at my friends house in Galicia in late February. Then suddenly, like almost every other place on the plant, I was unable to travel due to the alleged pandemic. As news of borders re-opening and travel being permitted once again started to circulate, I got the bike ready to move. I fitted new Mitas E-07 tires, carried out an oil and filter change, the engine tappets and the wheel spokes were adjusted as required, a new touring seat purchased and fitted, the brake fluid was changed and both calipers cleaned and greased. I got a set of custom made side plates to stop my soft throwover panniers tucking in on the back wheel and because of the broken rear indicator stem that I picked up when an old man in a car side swiped me in Italy the previous year, I got indicator protectors built in to the plates and once these were fitted the bike was good to go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/01-20.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 17 to 19 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:13:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-17&#34;&gt;Day 17&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days with a friend in Aix En Provence I said my goodbyes to him and headed for the Spanish border. Leaving Aix En Provence I headed West on the D7N, D572 and D6572 to Montpellier. The journey was pleasant enough in the early morning sun but these roads were too urbanised for my liking so, after circumventing Montpellier I took a short trip West on the A750 motorway until I found the D908 that headed West through the Languedoc National park area. This was a stunning road to ride in the warm early afternoon sunshine. Lots of beautiful scenery, very few cars on the road and the odd picturesque village to stop in and admire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/01-17.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/spain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 15:38:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/spain/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Spain are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&#xA;Like France, the motorways are the A roads, the main non-motorway roads are the N roads, and the smaller main roads are the C roads.&#xA;The motorways are all of a high standard but some are toll roads and some are not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 6 to 8 September 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:17:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lounging about in the sun and riding some forest dirt roads in Galicia to reacquaint myself with riding off road it was time to head back to Krakow in Poland where I planned to spend the Winter. After saying my goodbyes in Galicia I set off for the East coast of Spain. I took the N120 from Monforete De lemos to Ponferrada and although this is a fast main road it is quite pleasant to ride on with a bike as it twists and turns as it climbs up the valley of the river Sil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/01-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 August 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain 2019 and Two Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-2019-two-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:40:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-2019-two-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.. the story so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left the city of Reus in in December 2018 for the home of my good friend in Galicia, with only a vague idea about what I wanted to do next. En route I decided to visit the city of Leon, a city that I had always wanted to see but had never actually gotten around to visiting. Leon lived up to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:40:22 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it was 1 year ago that I left Scotland behind to make my journey around the world and I arrived in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from my earlier posts, I decided to stay in Spain for 2 years to learn the language as I knew that it would be an invaluable asset on my journey around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what has the 1st year of my journey been like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Break in the Country</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/a-little-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 09:10:42 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/a-little-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is nothing better to lift the spirits than a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, in the middle of July I took the bike out and rode it 1000 km to my friend&amp;rsquo;s house in Galicia. Not a cloud in the sky, 40 degrees and the whole journey I managed to do in (Ahem!) hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At The Zoo</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 19:33:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On arriving in Reus I spent my first uneventful week in the city at a local hotel and I, with some local assistance, attempted to find a suitable place to rent. However, as I was soon to learn, nothing happens quickly in Spain and by the time my check out date was fast approaching I was still no further forward. As the hotel was fully booked for the next week I managed to secure a holiday apartment for two weeks just between the holiday towns of Salou and Cambrils.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks beside the sea what could be better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/01-zoo.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unshackled Life</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/an-unshackled-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/an-unshackled-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once I had spent a relaxing night in Santiago de Compostela I boarded a train to the town of Monforte de Lemos which is near to the village where my good friend stays. I had purchased a ticket online (in Spanish) the previous evening and on boarding the train I found that my Spanish was not as good as I had hoped.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the ticket price was 24 Euros for the 70 odd mile journey I had assumed that it was a standard fare but when I took my numbered seat I was quickly ejected from it by an elderly Spanish woman who thrust her ticket under my nose whilst at the same time shouting loudly and pointing at me. Surely the train company had not issued two tickets for the same seat?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over The Finish Line</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 18:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/01-sant.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once my house had eventually been sold it was time for me to leave the UK for good. I hired a car, said my farewells and drove off to England for a few days to do likewise with my friends South of the border. A few days later I was on a plane heading for the next part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part Two</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:25:03 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Northwest of Spain where my friend lives reminds me of Scotland, it is a place full of mountains, tree covered slopes, and deep dark bodies of water. Like Scotland for about two or three months of the year it is cold, it is cloudy, and it rains a lot but this is where the similarities end as for the rest of the year it is sunny and warm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/01-gal.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part One</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:17:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I departed the UK on 14 December 2016 astride my bike sort of as planned (more on this later) and yes it did feel as good as I thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a cold but uneventful 500 mile journey I arrived at Folkestone to drive on to the train that would take me out of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/01-bike.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
