<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovenia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/slovenia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovenia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 10:53:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/slovenia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Slovenia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 10:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/slovenia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Slovenia are 50 km/h (31 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, 110 km/h (68 mph) on dual carriageways and 130 km/h (81 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Slovenia the motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter A, the non motorway main roads are numbered, the smaller roads have the name of the place that the road lead to on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 91 to 94 Bosnia, Croatia, Slovenia and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-91&#34;&gt;Day 91&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-91&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I set off North from Sarajevo to Banja Luka which on arrival I found to be a very nondescript city, so deciding not to stop there, I then continued riding and headed West for the Croatian border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/01-92.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst the scenery in Bosnia was reasonably pleasant, like my time in Serbia, I found very little to hold my attention and like Serbia, it is not a country that I will return to. I crossed the border in to Croatia and I headed West to the coast. I stopped at the first reasonable sized town and I was able to get some Croatian money from an ATM. Luckily I had made better calculations than I had in Serbia so I had no Bosnian cash to try to get rid of, which was fortunate because yet again there were no money exchange facilities at the border crossing. A few weeks before setting off on the trip, I had encountered post in somewhere or other about a guy who ran a small operation hosting bikers in the spare rooms of his house, so having made contact with him I headed for his place. The guy used to run a motorbike shop in England and provided me with very comfortable accommodation for around 20 Euros a night. I stayed for 3 nights to get a bit of a break and to attend to an oil change and some minor tinkering here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
