<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Central America - A Personal Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</guid>
      <description>Costa RicaCosta Rica is a very expensive country when compared to all of the other countries that I have visited in Central America. I had mixed feelings about my time in the country, the Caribbean side is a complete dump but still as expensive as the rest of the country which in parts was also a dump.&#xA;The Capital city San Jose for example, was pretty grubby and the public parks that I visited in the centre of the city were full of drunks sleeping on the grass or on the park benches, and both parks stank of stale urine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</guid>
      <description>Seven Years DownIt is now April 2024 and it has been 7 years since I left the UK to commence what I thought would be an around the world trip on my bike and my goodness how the world has changed!&#xA;At the beginning of 2020 the world descended in to insanity and madness and, to me at least, it seems that no meaningful recovery to sanity has yet been achieved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</guid>
      <description>Six Years DownAs I sit here in the city of Reus in Spain contemplating the choice of destination for continuing my RTW trip on my bike, I sometimes reflect on the six years that have passed since I permanently left the UK. When I think about my travels on my bike throughout Europe in those six years it seems only months ago that I started my journey, however, when I think about the madness that the world has descended in to since 2020 it seems like an eternity has passed and that nightmare will never end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 End of Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my RTW trip properly when I bought my Himalayan in August of 2019. Since then, just over 3 years later, I have visited every country in Europe that I wished to see and covered about 34,000 miles (57,600 km) doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/01-pt1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Years Down And Who Would Have Guessed?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-years-down&#34;&gt;Five Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#five-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been five years since I left Scotland to begin my Round The World trip (RTW) and who would have guessed how the world would have so dramatically changed since April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/01-fyd.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 46 September 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:57:01 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-45&#34;&gt;Day 45&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-45&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 days off the bike I needed to get going again so I left Sofia in the pouring rain and headed South East in the direction of Plovdiv. My reasons for visiting Plovdiv were twofold, firstly I had read that this city was the oldest continually inhabited city in Europe and secondly, as I wanted to visit Greece, I needed to get tested for the alleged virus and a hospital in Plovdiv provided this service. I booked in to a modern hotel a short walk from the old town for 4 nights at about 30 Euros per night. While I waited on being tested I explored the city and found that the city had a lot of excavated Roman architecture still visible in the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/01-45.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Covid Lockdowns and Three Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</guid>
      <description>The Madness BeginsAbout a week or so after I arrived at my friend&amp;rsquo;s home in Galcia I started to hear media reports of an outbreak of the Covid 19 virus in the Cremona area of Northern Italy where a large number of people were apparently getting very ill and or dying, apparently as a result of being infected by this virus.&#xA;Once I realised that I had passed through the epicentre of the Italian outbreak two days before I had my bout of fever, I looked up some of the known symptoms etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:48:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in the city of Opole about a month ago and I must say that of the little of Poland that I have seen, I like this country. In places Poland reminds me of Scotland as it used to be about 40 years ago and in other places it looks just like any other modern European country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:40:22 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it was 1 year ago that I left Scotland behind to make my journey around the world and I arrived in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from my earlier posts, I decided to stay in Spain for 2 years to learn the language as I knew that it would be an invaluable asset on my journey around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what has the 1st year of my journey been like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over The Finish Line</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 18:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/01-sant.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once my house had eventually been sold it was time for me to leave the UK for good. I hired a car, said my farewells and drove off to England for a few days to do likewise with my friends South of the border. A few days later I was on a plane heading for the next part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Another Rant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 12:56:45 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have updated this blog, a lot has happened to me since my last post so I shall start where I left off. After leaving my bike at the home of my friend in Galicia I flew back to the UK and arrived a Stanstead airport only to find that my flight to Glasgow was delayed by a couple of hours by snow on the runways, however eventually the plane took off and I was Scotland bound once again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I travelled from Glasgow airport to my home the views of Glasgow from the motorway made my heart sink like the Titanic and like it, I hit rock bottom very quickly. On my way hoe I stopped at a large supermarket to get some provisions and was quickly reminded of the lack of common courtesy displayed by most people who shop there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Cluttering of a Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 09:11:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent dismantling of my present life in preparation for the next part of my life I have found to be an unexpectedly cathartic experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The de-cluttering of a life is something I can now definitely recommend and whether the de-cluttering is solely of unused physical possessions or otherwise is up to you, but it is a process that for me has prompted a realisation that it is perhaps something that I should have done a long time ago. I was surprised at the quantity of items that I possessed for which I had no real use. I may have had a use for them at one time in my life but there they sat in the cupboard, loft, or drawer willing me to hang on to them for just another year, just in case….&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons For Departure...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 11:33:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fully expected that the next post that I made in this blog would be something to do with my bike and how it is now serviced and ready to hurtle off towards the setting sun&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However one of the many reasons as to why I have taken a dislike to this country has just sneaked up and prodded me in the eye. I should know better by now but against my better judgement I had a quick look at the evening news as hosted by the BBC (Biased Broadcasting Corporation) only to be informed that as a result of BREXIT, inflation is on the rise and prices of goods including petrol are expected to rise as a result. I get that, with a weaker pound imported products will cost more, but petrol?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is news to me but according to the upper class twit the BBC produced to explain to the assembled peasantry, the UK apparently buys its oil in US Dollars and since the pound has fallen against the dollar oil is therefore more expensive to buy. Like the argument for imported goods this sounds reasonable unless you are an adult with an IQ over 20, semi-literate, and or live in central Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
