<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 154 to 156 Iquique to Taltal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/154-156/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/154-156/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-154&#34;&gt;Day 154&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-154&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off early and I climbed back out of Iqieque and back on to Route 5 South where I refuelled shorty after re-joining it. I was in for yet another 150 mile stretch of empty road before I would get to the next petrol station. It was cold but at least it was sunny and there were no head winds. I had done about 80 miles when I encountered another customs checkpoint in the middle of nowhere. There was a large bus stopped in it and all of the passengers had to disembark and have their bags and documents checked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 144 Colombia to Ecuador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-144&#34;&gt;Day 144&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-144&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was overcast when I left my hotel in San Juan and headed for the border. I arrived there at about half past eight in the morning and it was busy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/144/13-144.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I parked the bike outside the immigration and customs building and I was immediately approached by a guy who wanted to change my Colombian pesos for USD which they use in Ecuador. The guy gave me a competitive rate so I changed what I had and then he offered to watch my bike for me whilst I went to immigration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 136 to 137 Medellin to Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-136&#34;&gt;Day 136&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-136&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Medellin at around seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, it was overcast and it looked as if it was about to rain but I had high hopes of staying dry once I had gotten out of the city and I was heading in the direction of the Caribbean coast. I had a brief entanglement with the morning rush hour traffic but as I was heading out of the city rather than in to it I managed to avoid the worst of the traffic chaos. I eventually found the correct road, the Autopista al Mar 1, and I headed up in to the mountains to the North of the city and within a half an hour I was clear of Medellin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;Arrving in South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the bike had been left at the airport and after a night in Panama city on the beer and cigars with my friends, I made my way to the airport to catch my flight to Bogota. The flight was scheduled to leave at 3:25 pm and to arrive in Bogota at 5:10 pm. I boarded the plane and the 3:25 pm departure time came and went with all of us still sitting in the plane on the airport standing waiting to taxi. The plane started moving around 3:40 pm and the plane began taxiing, and taxiing, and taxiing. I thought that it was going all of the way in to Panama city. Eventually at 4:05 pm the plane took off. Now either the plane was much faster than usual or the hanging around on the plane at the airport in Panama is included in the flight time because after an uneventful flight it landed at Bogota at the scheduled arrival time of 5:10 pm. Very strange!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;Getting Ready For South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the time had come for me to stop loitering about Panama City like a bad smell and get myself and the bike to Colombia to start the South American part of my trip. It is now turning Summer in South America and I wanted to reach Tierra Del Fuego during the good weather window between the start of January and the end of March so it was time to get my arse in gear and get things moving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central America - A Personal Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;costa-rica&#34;&gt;Costa Rica&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#costa-rica&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Costa Rica is a very expensive country when compared to all of the other countries that I have visited in Central America. I had mixed feelings about my time in the country, the Caribbean side is a complete dump but still as expensive as the rest of the country which in parts was also a dump.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Capital city San Jose for example, was pretty grubby and the public parks that I visited in the centre of the city were full of drunks sleeping on the grass or on the park benches, and both parks stank of stale urine. However, the scenery in the country once away from the Capital city was awesome, especially in the coffee growing area of San Marcos that I stayed in, but it was also very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;seven-years-down&#34;&gt;Seven Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#seven-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is now April 2024 and it has been 7 years since I left the UK to commence what I thought would be an around the world trip on my bike and my goodness how the world has changed!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2020 the world descended in to insanity and madness and, to me at least, it seems that no meaningful recovery to sanity has yet been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;six-years-down&#34;&gt;Six Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#six-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I sit here in the city of Reus in Spain contemplating the choice of destination for continuing my RTW trip on my bike, I sometimes reflect on the six years that have passed since I permanently left the UK. When I think about my travels on my bike throughout Europe in those six years it seems only months ago that I started my journey, however, when I think about the madness that the world has descended in to since 2020 it seems like an eternity has passed and that nightmare will never end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 End of Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my RTW trip properly when I bought my Himalayan in August of 2019. Since then, just over 3 years later, I have visited every country in Europe that I wished to see and covered about 34,000 miles (57,600 km) doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/01-pt1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In covering those miles I have ridden for just 98 days of actual travelling, which averages out at around 350 miles (590 km) per day. 98 days of actual travelling in 3 years, not a lot!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Years Down And Who Would Have Guessed?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-years-down&#34;&gt;Five Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#five-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been five years since I left Scotland to begin my Round The World trip (RTW) and who would have guessed how the world would have so dramatically changed since April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/01-fyd.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since leaving, I have travelled in excess of forty thousand miles on my bike(s) and yet I find myself still in Europe. The reasons for this are a combination of my own tardiness and the world shutting down in 2020. As I wait, hoping that I will soon be able to continue with my RTW trip, my thoughts about the dramatic changes that have taken place in the world over the past two years have made me wonder in what direction the world will now move because of those changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 Poland, Germany and France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 47 to 52 Bulgaria and Greece to Turkish Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/47-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:23:31 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/47-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-47&#34;&gt;Day 47&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-47&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the madness I had to pre book my accommodation in Greece and pass the details to the Greek government before entry, therefore once I entered Greece I had to get from the border crossing to the port of Igoumenitsa on the West of Greece to cross over to the island of Corfu and because I was travelling a large distance to catch a ferry, a full day on the Greek motorways and an early start was required. It was still dark when I loaded up the bike and set off for the border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 46 Bulgaria to Greek Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:57:01 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-45&#34;&gt;Day 45&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-45&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 days off the bike I needed to get going again so I left Sofia in the pouring rain and headed South East in the direction of Plovdiv. My reasons for visiting Plovdiv were twofold, firstly I had read that this city was the oldest continually inhabited city in Europe and secondly, as I wanted to visit Greece, I needed to get tested for the alleged virus and a hospital in Plovdiv provided this service. I booked in to a modern hotel a short walk from the old town for 4 nights at about 30 Euros per night. While I waited on being tested I explored the city and found that the city had a lot of excavated Roman architecture still visible in the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Covid Lockdowns and Three Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-madness-begins&#34;&gt;The Madness Begins&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-madness-begins&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;About a week or so after I arrived at my friend&amp;rsquo;s home in Galcia I started to hear media reports of an outbreak of the Covid 19 virus in the Cremona area of Northern Italy where a large number of people were apparently getting very ill and or dying, apparently as a result of being infected by this virus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I realised that I had passed through the epicentre of the Italian outbreak two days before I had my bout of fever, I looked up some of the known symptoms etc. pertaining to this virus. Lo and behold an incubation period of two days and one of the lesser symptoms was fever and or shivers. However all I had was one night of fever and if one cares to look at fever as a symptom, the list of &amp;ldquo;diseases&amp;rdquo; that this can be attributed to is almost endless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 United Kingdom to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leaving Folkestone I boarded the train that travels under the English channel to France. I have done this a few times before and as usual I met some fellow two wheeled travellers on board. After 20 minutes or so of exchanging stories and thoughts about each other&amp;rsquo;s bikes, I said my farewells and rode South from Calais towards the city of Tours that would be my first stop on my way to Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:48:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in the city of Opole about a month ago and I must say that of the little of Poland that I have seen, I like this country. In places Poland reminds me of Scotland as it used to be about 40 years ago and in other places it looks just like any other modern European country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/01-pol.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that there is very little money floating around this part of Poland, probably why so many Polish people travel to the UK and Germany to find better paid employment, and this is why some parts of this country remind me of Scotland during the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:40:22 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it was 1 year ago that I left Scotland behind to make my journey around the world and I arrived in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from my earlier posts, I decided to stay in Spain for 2 years to learn the language as I knew that it would be an invaluable asset on my journey around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what has the 1st year of my journey been like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over The Finish Line</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 18:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/01-sant.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once my house had eventually been sold it was time for me to leave the UK for good. I hired a car, said my farewells and drove off to England for a few days to do likewise with my friends South of the border. A few days later I was on a plane heading for the next part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plane that I was on had departed from Stanstead airport a few hours earlier but as it was approaching Santiago airport in the North West of Spain my vice-like grip on my seat began to loosen. Ever since as a young police officer I attended the crash site of flight Pan Am 103 that was blown out of the sky over the town of Lockerbie in Southern Scotland one evening in December 1988, I have, for obvious reasons, always disliked flying. As the wheels of the plane touched the runway, and much to the consternation of the somewhat refined middle class English woman sitting next to me I burst out laughing. Due to what I have previously written here of my dislike of flying, you would assume that it was some sort of reaction to a sudden release of tension and apparently so did the woman next to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Another Rant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 12:56:45 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have updated this blog, a lot has happened to me since my last post so I shall start where I left off. After leaving my bike at the home of my friend in Galicia I flew back to the UK and arrived a Stanstead airport only to find that my flight to Glasgow was delayed by a couple of hours by snow on the runways, however eventually the plane took off and I was Scotland bound once again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Cluttering of a Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 09:11:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent dismantling of my present life in preparation for the next part of my life I have found to be an unexpectedly cathartic experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The de-cluttering of a life is something I can now definitely recommend and whether the de-cluttering is solely of unused physical possessions or otherwise is up to you, but it is a process that for me has prompted a realisation that it is perhaps something that I should have done a long time ago. I was surprised at the quantity of items that I possessed for which I had no real use. I may have had a use for them at one time in my life but there they sat in the cupboard, loft, or drawer willing me to hang on to them for just another year, just in case….&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons For Departure...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 11:33:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fully expected that the next post that I made in this blog would be something to do with my bike and how it is now serviced and ready to hurtle off towards the setting sun&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However one of the many reasons as to why I have taken a dislike to this country has just sneaked up and prodded me in the eye. I should know better by now but against my better judgement I had a quick look at the evening news as hosted by the BBC (Biased Broadcasting Corporation) only to be informed that as a result of BREXIT, inflation is on the rise and prices of goods including petrol are expected to rise as a result. I get that, with a weaker pound imported products will cost more, but petrol?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
