<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poland on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/poland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poland on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/poland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 79 to 81 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-79&#34;&gt;Day 79&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-79&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world is still mad and borders are still shut because of the alleged virus, or wars, or other political nonsense, and all roads East from Central Europe are still closed. So, its on the merry go round once again and back to Spain to visit my friend. However, this time the Balkans are open for business (well apart from Kosovo and Serbia going at it again!) so I decided to take the opportunity to visit these countries whilst I can. Therefore on 15th August 2022 I headed South from Krakow and took the road from there to the Southern Polish city of Bielsko-Biala. I had never actually been here before so this was a perfect time for a visit and I found it to be quite surprising. The town was obviously fortified at some time and the nicer part of the town is to be found within these walls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/01-79.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 January 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you are all aware my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 August 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years Down and the Tatra Mountains</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:48:57 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has now been 4 years since I left the UK on my adventures, however, as I mentioned in my previous post because of all of the madness engendered in politicians in respect of restrictions on individual movement I am unable to travel much and I am presently marking time in Krakow in Poland. I just thought that I would post this update on my stalled RTW trip and to share a few photographs of my jaunts around Southern Poland in to the Tatra Mountains and around Krakow during the last few months of captivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Krynica Area of Southern Poland&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/01-tm.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 34 to 38 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 18:39:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-34&#34;&gt;Day 34&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-34&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I had finished with my coaching I resumed my travels and I headed North to Warsaw. I stayed in a small hotel on the edge of Warsaw for under 30 Euros and I was able to take the metro in to the city centre which I walked about in for a while, I also found that the old town was somewhat touristy but nonetheless quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/01-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 August 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Poland</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/poland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 17:11:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/poland/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Poland are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways&#xA;The motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter A. Some of the motorways or stretches of a motorway are toll roads but most are not. The main non-motorway roads are also just numbered, and the smaller main roads are also just numbered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the UK 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:48:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in the city of Opole about a month ago and I must say that of the little of Poland that I have seen, I like this country. In places Poland reminds me of Scotland as it used to be about 40 years ago and in other places it looks just like any other modern European country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
