<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Turkey on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/turkey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Turkey on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 15:51:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/turkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Turkey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 15:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/turkey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Turkey are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 120 km/h (74 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Turkey the motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter D, the non motorway main roads are numbered and also prefixed with the letter D, the smaller roads just have the names of the town that they lead to on the signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 65 to 67 Turkey, Bulgaria and Moldovian Border to Romania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-65&#34;&gt;Day 65&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-65&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for leaving Turkey was because all of the land routes to the East from Turkey were closed and because of this I had to decide where to go for the winter. Staying in Turkey was an option but having a 90 day limit to my stay would have meant having to leave Turkey at the end of January to go back a European country. Another factor for consideration was the potential for the alleged virus to affect border crossings at the end of January in to February. As the borders were still open at that time I decided that it would be better to make that journey in early November rather than at the beginning of February. I left Kırklareli early the next day and headed for the Bulgarian border. On approaching the border the road rose sharply and in the shaded parts, the road was covered in frost. A few minutes at the border and I was once again in Bulgaria. I rode along the coast past Burgas and Varna, I only stopped for fuel and coffee as it was not warming up and it had become overcast. I was at the Romanian border by late afternoon and once through I headed for the unremarkable city of Constanta where I spent the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 62 to 64 Turkey Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:39:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-62&#34;&gt;Day 62&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-62&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road to Antalya was very open and the route that I had chosen swept South down from the mountains&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/00-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/01-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and then along the shore of a large lake and eventually via some boring fast dual carriageway heading to the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/02-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/03-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did stop at the side of the road for a cup of tea and found that the resteraunt specialised in fish, you just had to pick which one that you wanted to eat!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aizanoi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aizanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 12:52:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aizanoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;The Greek/Roman City of Aizanoi&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site was one of the best and undeveloped sites that I have yet encountered on my travels. Apart from a partially complete temple, the site had row upon row of stone carvings that were used to decorate the many buildings that used to stand on this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most amazing things on this site was a complete underground vault that had survived from when it was originally constructed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/aizanoi/01-az.JPG&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 59 to 61 Turkey Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:19:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-59&#34;&gt;Day 59&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-59&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After out encounter with the wolves the previous night we decided that later that day we would spend a night in a hotel so we set off to head for the city of Eskisehir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/01-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As usual we took some smaller scenic routes and at a lesiurely pace I was able to stop to take the odd photo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/02-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/03-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/04-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and then eventually we headed for our hotel in the city of Eskisehir.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 56 to 58 Turkey Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:19:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-56&#34;&gt;Day 56&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-56&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending 2 nights in the city we set off again up in to the mountains that sit to the south of the city and our first stop was to look at a tree which allegedly over 600 years old, it was certainly the biggest tree that I have ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/01-56.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/02-56.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then we rode up to the top of the mountain and to a viewpoint where we could see the enormous size of the city far below us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 53 to 55 Turkey Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 19:34:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-53&#34;&gt;Day 53&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-53&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/01-53.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the the Greek and Turkish border under a cloudy sky which looked like it could produce some rain. After the usual rounds of producing my passport and bike ownership documents to the Greek and Turkish border and customs officials, I was almost cleared to enter Turkey. However, I first had to go to one of the buildings at the border and purchase insurance that covered me for riding my bike in Turkey. For the price of about 15 Euros I obtained 90 days cover. Now I was in Turkey and I set off for Isatnbul. The rain was light and came and went and I was getting a bit bored and then I saw this at the side of the road. A Boeing 737 restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
