<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macedonia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/macedonia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macedonia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 18:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/macedonia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in North Macedonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/macedonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 18:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/macedonia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in North Macedonia are 50 km/h (31 mph) in built up areas, 80 km/h (50 mph) outside built up areas, and 120 km/h (78 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In North Macedonia the motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter A, the non motorway main roads are numbered and prefixed with the letter R, the smaller roads just have the names of the town that they lead to on the signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 85 to 87 North Macedonia to Albania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-85&#34;&gt;Day 85&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-85&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, after breakfast I headed West through the mountains in the direction of the Albanian border crossing at Lake Ohrid, however, as I was nearing the border I saw the dark clouds massing and just managed to get in to a petrol station before an enormous thunderstorm rolled in keeping me drinking coffee for nearly 2 hours until it passed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/01-85.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I eventually crossed the Albanian border it was late in the afternoon so my first task was to get a SIM card and cash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 Hungary and Serbia to North Macedonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is quite a well spread out city that is much longer East to West that in its from North to South. The city does not have a central square and this seems to be a thing in Slovakia, Hungary and other countries to the South of Europe, instead it has an elongated main street on which most of the shops, bars, and cafes are located. From my experiences it seems to me that central squares seem to be more prevalent in Northern European countries for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
