<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guatemala on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/guatemala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guatemala on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 17:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/guatemala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Guatemala</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/guatemala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/guatemala/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Guatemala are 40 km/h (25 mph) or 60 km/h (37 mph) in built up areas, outside built up areas all roads are limited to 80 km/h (50 mph)&#xA;All of the road signs for the main roads are Green with White writing and the local roads are Blue with White writing.&#xA;The main roads in Guatemla are either tarmac or concrete and they are all generally very good and reasonably well maintained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 125 to 126 May 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/125-126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/125-126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-125&#34;&gt;Day 125&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-125&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I took a few days off in Antigua Guatemala right across the road from my hotel was a bike shop so I took the opportunity to have the guys who ran the shop try to straighten out my rear wheel ABS rotor. As the bike had just turned 5000 miles on the clock I asked them to change the engine oil while they were at it. They told me that they had straightened the rotor for me but the malfunction on the rear ABS is still there, I will probably need to buy a new ABS rotor on my return to Panama city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had planned a short riding day, my destination for the day was Port San Jose on the Pacific coast some 50 miles or so away. I left Antigua Guatemala about 10 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and to be honest ride there was pretty uninspiring because the heat haze was very thick and I could not see very much. I arrived at my destination at about 1 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and eventually found my hotel no thanks to Google maps that had me going in circles for about an hour. Once unpacked I got changed and headed out in a 3 wheeled taxi to have a look at the beach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/125-126/01-125.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 123 to 124 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-123&#34;&gt;Day 123&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-123&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my accommodation in Coban at just after 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and set off for the city of Huehuetenango which I had decided to ride to that day. Google maps showed that Huehuetenango was just over 120 miles away but the time to do it was show as nearly 5 hours so I knew to expect some slow going in parts of my journey for the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as I left Coban I saw a really nice roadside restaurant so I pulled in for coffee and breakfast, steak with scrambled eggs for 35 Quetzals (4.50 US Dollars)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/01-123.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 121 to 122 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-121&#34;&gt;Day 121&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-121&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was another hot day in Honduras, when I set off from Puerto Cortes at 7 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was already displaying 33 degrees Celsius on my bike. I headed for the Guatemalan border that was about an hour away and as the road passed close to the coast I stopped to take a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/01-121.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
