<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 Ecuador to Peru</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-147&#34;&gt;Day 147&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-147&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left Huaquillas and headed back out of town to take the road to the vehicular border crossing. When I arrived at the Ecuadorian side of the border crossing I found that only the customs were located there so I headed in to the office to have my TIP cancelled. This was done very quickly at not cost. Ten minutes later I rode the 4 miles or so over the International bridge to the Peruvian side of the border where I parked the bike and went to find the Peruvian immigration office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 148 to 149 Chiclayo to Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-148&#34;&gt;Day 148&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-148&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set of from Chiclayo at about seven o’clock in the morning and I headed South on the main road out of the city. After a couple of hours on the road I stopped in the city of Trujillo to have some breakfast and to put on an extra layer as once again there was a strong cool wind. This time it was blowing some mist in from the sea. On my way out of the city after breakfast I stopped to photograph another example of the appalling litter problem. It was so bad that even as I was riding I could smell the stench of decaying something or other every time I passed something like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
