<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 148 to 149 Chiclayo to Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-148&#34;&gt;Day 148&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-148&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set of from Chiclayo at about seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and I headed South on the main road out of the city. After a couple of hours on the road I stopped in the city of Trujillo to have some breakfast and to put on an extra layer as once again there was a strong cool wind. This time it was blowing some mist in from the sea. On my way out of the city after breakfast I stopped to photograph another example of the appalling litter problem. It was so bad that even as I was riding I could smell the stench of decaying something or other every time I passed something like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 Ecuador to Peru</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-147&#34;&gt;Day 147&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-147&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took the road back out of Huaquillas and headed for the border. I stopped at the Ecuadorian side to find out that only the Customs were located there so I only had to to cancel my TIP. The process took all of ten minutes and then I rode for about 3 miles until I crossed the actual border and arrived at the Peruvian side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/147/01-147.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both of the Ecuadorian and Peruvian immigration offices are located in the same office so after getting stamped out of Ecuador I just moved to the next window and got stamped in to Peru. The whole process took about twenty minutes as there was a small queue. Then I went to the Peruvian customs to get my TIP. They only needed to see my original bike registration, my passport, my driving licence, and that was all. No copies of anything, such a refreshing change from Central America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
