<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peru on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/peru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 153 Peru to Chile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/153/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/153/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-153&#34;&gt;Day 153&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-153&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the the border at around half past seven in the morning and it was relatively quiet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/153/01-153.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The border post was a joint operation between Peru and Chile but there were no signs to indicate which were the immigration windows or which were the customs windows. However after a bit of messing about I eventually found the Peruvian immigration window and got stamped out of Peru but I had to complete a small form in duplicate with my bike details on it and this also got stamped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 150 to 152 Lima to Tacna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/150-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/150-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-150&#34;&gt;Day 150&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-150&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the insane traffic in Lima I decided to get an early start to my day to see if I could avoid the worst of it so I left my hotel early at half past six in the morning however it was to no avail as the roads were already full of traffic. It took me over an hour to get out of the city and once I had ridden for about 30 miles or so I stopped to refuel and to have a coffee. I had put another layer on just in case I encountered the sea mist and shortly after I set off again I rode in to it. It did not clear till around ten o&amp;rsquo;clock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-lima&#34;&gt;Impressions of Lima&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-lima&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/01-lim.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Lima at around three o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon so I thought that I had plenty of time to see the city before it got dark. My hotel was in the Los Olivos district which was in the North of the city so I decided to take an Uber down to a fortress called Fortaleza del Real Felipe which is on the sea front and around which I presumed the old part of the city would be located. Due to the traffic it took me about 40 minutes to travel 5 miles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 148 to 149 Chiclayo to Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-148&#34;&gt;Day 148&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-148&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set of from Chiclayo at about seven o’clock in the morning and I headed South on the main road out of the city. After a couple of hours on the road I stopped in the city of Trujillo to have some breakfast and to put on an extra layer as once again there was a strong cool wind but this time the wind was also blowing some mist in from the sea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 Ecuador to Peru</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-147&#34;&gt;Day 147&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-147&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left Huaquillas and headed back out of town to take the road to the vehicular border crossing. When I arrived at the Ecuadorian side of the border crossing I found that only the customs were located there so I headed in to the office to have my TIP cancelled. This was done very quickly at not cost. Ten minutes later I rode the 4 miles or so over the International bridge to the Peruvian side of the border where I parked the bike and went to find the Peruvian immigration office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
