<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Czech Republic on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/czech-republic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Czech Republic on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/czech-republic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 August 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Czech Republic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/czech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:11:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/czech/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in the Czech Republic are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&#xA;The motorways are are just numbered and although they are toll roads they are free for motorbikes, the main non-motorway roads are also just numbered, and the smaller main roads just have road names.&#xA;The motorways signs are in Green, the main road signs are in Blue, and signs for the smaller roads are white.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 September 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
