<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Czech Republic on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/czech-republic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Czech Republic on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/czech-republic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I crossed the border in to the Czech Republic in the rain and rode across to the other side of the county but all the while it continued to rain intermittently. I only stopped for petrol and then moved on trying to get to my destination for that day, the city of Brno as quickly as I could. As I arrived in Brno I got caught in a huge thunderstorm and I got thoroughly soaked before reaching my accommodation for the night. Once sorted out, as the rain had passed I walked in to Brno old town and I found it to be quite pleasant, however, the walk in was not quite as nice. There were lots of people hanging around street corners in large groups, mostly men in the twenties and although they never hassled me, I felt a certain tension in the air. In addition, the streets where these groups were congregating were full of litter and graffiti covered almost every wall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Czech Republic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/czech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:11:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/czech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in the Czech Republic are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are are just numbered and although they are toll roads they are free for motorbikes, the main non-motorway roads are also just numbered, and the smaller main roads just have road names.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways signs are in Green, the main road signs are in Blue, and signs for the smaller roads are white.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 France, Italy, Switzerland, Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things that I have noticed during my riding through France is that the road numbers can suddenly change without warning. For example the D133 that I started on changed mysteriously after about 10 miles and became the D541. Unless one keeps a close eye on this it can get very confusing. Yes, I know a Sat Nav would make this point irrelevant but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I like to travel. Riding further East towards Gap I could see the mountains start to rise in the distance. It had been several years since I had ridden over any Alpine passes and I was looking forward to it but by now the sun was strong, it was very warm, and the scenery forced me to stop, not only to capture its beauty and grandeur but also to pause and soak it all up over a cup of coffee or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
