<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>January 2024 End of Part Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-out-of-chile&#34;&gt;Getting Out Of Chile&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#getting-out-of-chile&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So at four o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon I left the squalid house in Taltal. I took everything that I owned related to my bike to the &amp;ldquo;workshop&amp;rdquo;, dumped it there, and I then headed for the bus station. No one asked me where I was going so I never told them that I was abandoning the bike along with all of my bike related belongings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did consider telling them what my intentions were but to be honest because of the way that they had behaved towards me in trying to wring as much money from me as possible, I decided not to tell them what I was about to do. I knew that once I did not return then my bike, my bags, and all of my bike related possessions would become their problem to deal with and not mine. Although I should have felt guilty about that I did not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 154 to 156 Iquique to Taltal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/154-156/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/154-156/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-154&#34;&gt;Day 154&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-154&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off early and I climbed back out of Iqieque and back on to Route 5 South where I refuelled shorty after re-joining it. I was in for yet another 150 mile stretch of empty road before I would get to the next petrol station. It was cold but at least it was sunny and there were no head winds. I had done about 80 miles when I encountered another customs checkpoint in the middle of nowhere. There was a large bus stopped in it and all of the passengers had to disembark and have their bags and documents checked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 153 Peru to Chile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/153/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/153/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-153&#34;&gt;Day 153&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-153&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the the border at around half past seven in the morning and it was relatively quiet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/153/01-153.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The border post was a joint operation between Peru and Chile but there were no signs to indicate which were the immigration windows or which were the customs windows. However after a bit of messing about I eventually found the Peruvian immigration window and got stamped out of Peru but I had to complete a small form in duplicate with my bike details on it and this also got stamped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 150 to 152 Lima to Tacna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/150-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/150-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-150&#34;&gt;Day 150&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-150&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the insane traffic in Lima I decided to get an early start to my day to see if I could avoid the worst of it so I left my hotel early at half past six in the morning however it was to no avail as the roads were already full of traffic. It took me over an hour to get out of the city and once I had ridden for about 30 miles or so I stopped to refuel and to have a coffee. I had put another layer on just in case I encountered the sea mist and shortly after I set off again I rode in to it. It did not clear till around ten o&amp;rsquo;clock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-lima&#34;&gt;Impressions of Lima&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-lima&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/lima/01-lim.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Lima at around three o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon so I thought that I had plenty of time to see the city before it got dark. My hotel was in the Los Olivos district which was in the North of the city so I decided to take an Uber down to a fortress called Fortaleza del Real Felipe which is on the sea front and around which I presumed the old part of the city would be located. Due to the traffic it took me about 40 minutes to travel 5 miles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 148 to 149 Chiclayo to Lima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/148-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-148&#34;&gt;Day 148&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-148&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set of from Chiclayo at about seven o’clock in the morning and I headed South on the main road out of the city. After a couple of hours on the road I stopped in the city of Trujillo to have some breakfast and to put on an extra layer as once again there was a strong cool wind but this time the wind was also blowing some mist in from the sea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 Ecuador to Peru</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-147&#34;&gt;Day 147&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-147&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left Huaquillas and headed back out of town to take the road to the vehicular border crossing. When I arrived at the Ecuadorian side of the border crossing I found that only the customs were located there so I headed in to the office to have my TIP cancelled. This was done very quickly at not cost. Ten minutes later I rode the 4 miles or so over the International bridge to the Peruvian side of the border where I parked the bike and went to find the Peruvian immigration office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 145 to 146 Quito to Huaquillas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-145&#34;&gt;Day 145&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-145&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left Quito early and it was cold. The road out of the city climbed and climbed and at one point I got a break in the clouds from where I could take a photo of the city below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/01-145.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However just after I set off again I was back in to the clouds and climbing again. Once on the descent I encountered a road accident in the fast lane where a car had stuffed itself under the back of a bus in the heavy fog. The diesel tank of the bus had ruptured and it was running down the road but luckily for me the road was so steep that it all ran straight downhill in the outside lane and it did not flow across the road in to the inside lane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 144 Colombia to Ecuador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-144&#34;&gt;Day 144&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-144&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was overcast when I left my hotel in San Juan and headed for the border. I arrived there at about half past eight in the morning and it was busy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/144/13-144.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I parked the bike outside the immigration and customs building and I was immediately approached by a guy who wanted to change my Colombian pesos for USD which they use in Ecuador. The guy gave me a competitive rate so I changed what I had and then he offered to watch my bike for me whilst I went to immigration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 142 to 143 Neiva to San Juan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/142-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/142-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-142&#34;&gt;Day 142&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-142&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning as I prepared to leave my hotel it was overcast and the rain had just stopped. The previous evening I had looked at the map and I had decided to return to route 43 on which I would head South on but for some unknown reason I forgot about that and I headed South out of Neiva on route 45. The early morning air was quite cool and the further South I went the cooler it got and then it started to rain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 140 to 141 Santa Marta to Neiva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/140-141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/140-141/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-140&#34;&gt;Day 140&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-140&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of the 26th of December I said my farewells to my good friends Eric, Alison, and an Italian guy called Alessandro with whom I had become friends whilst we were both staying at the hostel. Alessandro had just bought himself a new Suzuki GN125F and he was in the process of running it in before heading South on a journey similar to mine. I then set off to start the biggest adventure of my life so far, to ride to my bike all the way to town of Ushuaia in the Tierra Del Fuego province of Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/santa-marta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/santa-marta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-santa-marta&#34;&gt;Impressions of Santa Marta&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-santa-marta&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I write this post I am currently in Santa Marta but by the time that it comes for me to leave I will have stayed in the city for about three weeks and so far I have really enjoyed my time here. I am planning to spend Christmas day in Santa Matra with two good friends whom I recently met in Panama city. My friends Eric and Allison are originally from Scotland but they emigrated to Canada over twenty years ago and meeting them in Panama was the first time that I had actually seen them since they left Scotland all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 139 La Guajira Desert to Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/139/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/139/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-139&#34;&gt;Day 139&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-139&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I got ready to leave Riohacha at about nine o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was a little bit cloudy which I was glad of as it was not as hot as it had been the previous morning. I quickly refuelled the bike and then I rode out of the town for a few miles on the main road North before turning on to the road that would eventually take me to the coastal town of Manaure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 138 Cartagena to Riohacha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/138/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-138&#34;&gt;Day 138&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-138&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was glad that it was eventually time to leave Cartagena and although it was Saurday morning I set off early in order to avoid any traffic only to find that there was some sort of cycle race taking place and the road out of the city was full of cyclists who were wandering all over the road.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I had negotiated my way out of the city without mowing down any of the cyclists that were making sudden and unannounced U turns in front of me, I headed for the city of Baranquilla which was about fifty miles further up the coast to the North. The road from Cartagena to Baranquilla was not particularly interesting apart from having to ride over a large but newish suspension bridge that spanned a wide river as I left Cartagena.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cartagena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cartagena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-cartagena&#34;&gt;Impressions of Cartagena&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-cartagena&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my way in to Cartagena I had to ride through the city at around four o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and as one can imagine it was complete chaos. Where I was staying was close to the old fortress that is a major landmark and tourist attraction for the city but this area is also at the Northernmost edge of the city so I had to ride through the the entire length of city to get to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 136 to 137 Medellin to Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-136&#34;&gt;Day 136&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-136&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Medellin at around seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, it was overcast and it looked as if it was about to rain but I had high hopes of staying dry once I had gotten out of the city and I was heading in the direction of the Caribbean coast. I had a brief entanglement with the morning rush hour traffic but as I was heading out of the city rather than in to it I managed to avoid the worst of the traffic chaos. I eventually found the correct road, the Autopista al Mar 1, and I headed up in to the mountains to the North of the city and within a half an hour I was clear of Medellin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medellin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/medellin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/medellin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-medellin&#34;&gt;Impressions of Medellin&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-medellin&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hotel in Medellin was situated in a good location about a ten minute walk North of the main train station. The city has an elevated metro system and a tram system together with lots of local buses. The two main metro lines and tram system lines converge at the San Antonio metro station which was about a five minute walk from where I was staying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought a card for the transport systems from the kiosk in the San Antonio metro station and it cost me about 3 USD including four journeys. The card that I bought allowed me use the metro, the tram, the buses, and the cable car system which I presumed was designed to take local residents up the steep slopes of the surrounding mountains on which lots of housing could be seen on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 134 to 135 Bogota to Medellin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/134-135/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/134-135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-134&#34;&gt;Day 134&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-134&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my hotel in Bogota at around seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, it was sunny and quite cool but at least it was not raining. I had just about reached the West side of the city when the traffic ground to a halt. For the next hour and a half I slowly filtered through the stationary traffic trying to get on to the road to Medellin. Because of the huge number of people in Colombia that use bikes as their everyday transport, even the filtering bikes were backed up for miles. Along with the other bikers I swapped lanes trying to get in to one that had a clear gap but every time one opened up all of the other bikers quickly filled up all of the available space between the lanes of stationary cars, buses, and lorries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bogota</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bogota/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bogota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-bogota&#34;&gt;Impressions of Bogota&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-bogota&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hotel in Bogota was situated in a good location near to the popular tourist neighbourhood of La Candelaria and close to a major pedestrian street full of shops and bars. This side of Bogota is bordered by some hills on top of which sits the church of Monserrate which is another favourite tourist spot. I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do the tourist bit but since I was in the city for a few days I decided to venture up to the top using the funicular railway. However once I got to the base of the hill there were large queues of people waiting to go up so that put paid to me going up as I hate queuing for such things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;Arrving in South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the bike had been left at the airport and after a night in Panama city on the beer and cigars with my friends, I made my way to the airport to catch my flight to Bogota. The flight was scheduled to leave at 3:25 pm and to arrive in Bogota at 5:10 pm. I boarded the plane and the 3:25 pm departure time came and went with all of us still sitting in the plane on the airport standing waiting to taxi. The plane started moving around 3:40 pm and the plane began taxiing, and taxiing, and taxiing. I thought that it was going all of the way in to Panama city. Eventually at 4:05 pm the plane took off. Now either the plane was much faster than usual or the hanging around on the plane at the airport in Panama is included in the flight time because after an uneventful flight it landed at Bogota at the scheduled arrival time of 5:10 pm. Very strange!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;Getting Ready For South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the time had come for me to stop loitering about Panama City like a bad smell and get myself and the bike to Colombia to start the South American part of my trip. It is now turning Summer in South America and I wanted to reach Tierra Del Fuego during the good weather window between the start of January and the end of March so it was time to get my arse in gear and get things moving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central America - A Personal Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-america--a-personal-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;costa-rica&#34;&gt;Costa Rica&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#costa-rica&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Costa Rica is a very expensive country when compared to all of the other countries that I have visited in Central America. I had mixed feelings about my time in the country, the Caribbean side is a complete dump but still as expensive as the rest of the country which in parts was also a dump.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Capital city San Jose for example, was pretty grubby and the public parks that I visited in the centre of the city were full of drunks sleeping on the grass or on the park benches, and both parks stank of stale urine. However, the scenery in the country once away from the Capital city was awesome, especially in the coffee growing area of San Marcos that I stayed in, but it was also very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 131 to 133 Nicaragua and Costa Rica to Panama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/131-133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/131-133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-131&#34;&gt;Day 131&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-131&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from the city of Granada at about 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and it was hot. I took the NIC-4 South in the direction of the border crossing at Pena Blanca. I stopped after about an hour for some breakfast at a roadside restaurant and then again about 20 miles from the border at a spot where the road ran close to the lake.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/131-133/01-131.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the border at about half past 10 in the morning and as usual I got stopped at the entrance to the border area, I had my passport checked and I was given my customs declaration form to complete. I parked up outside the main building and then went in to start another episode of the border pantomime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 129 to 130 El Salvador and Honduras to Nicaragua</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/129-130/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/129-130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-129&#34;&gt;Day 129&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-129&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left San Miguel at about 6 &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning as I knew that I had 2 borders to cross and I wanted to leave sufficient time to do this and get to a place to stay in Nicaragua before it got dark. It took me just about an hour to get to the El Salvadorian Honduran border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/129-130/01-129.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The El Salvadorian side was quick, I had to go to the customs first to get my TIP cancelled. That took all of 5 minutes at no cost. Then I rode about half a mile to the actual border and after my passport was checked I went to immigration. That took 10 minutes to get processed for leaving El Salvador and again at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 127 to 128 El Salvador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/127-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/127-128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-127&#34;&gt;Day 127&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-127&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending 2 nights at my accommodation in Santa Ana it was time to leave. Due to having to return to Panama to attend to some personal business, I have had to cut my Central America trip short. Now having no time to visit Mexico, it was time to start heading South towards Panama but not before taking another couple of days to explore El Salvador.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left Santa Ana at about 9 &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning heading generally South, and an hour later I had stopped for a coffee high above lake Coatepeque. The view was great except for the heat haze that restricted it somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 125 to 126 Guatemala to El Salvador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/125-126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/125-126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-125&#34;&gt;Day 125&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-125&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I took a few days off in Antigua Guatemala right across the road from my hotel was a bike shop so I took the opportunity to have the guys who ran the shop try to straighten out my rear wheel ABS rotor. As the bike had just turned 5000 miles on the clock I asked them to change the engine oil while they were at it. They told me that they had straightened the rotor for me but the malfunction on the rear ABS is still there, I will probably need to buy a new ABS rotor on my return to Panama city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 123 to 124 Guatemala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/123-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/123-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-123&#34;&gt;Day 123&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-123&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my accommodation in Coban at just after 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and set off for the city of Huehuetenango which I had decided to ride to that day. Google maps showed that Huehuetenango was just over 120 miles away but the time to do it was show as nearly 5 hours so I knew to expect some slow going in parts of my journey for the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 121 to 122 Honduras to Guatemala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/121-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/121-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-121&#34;&gt;Day 121&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-121&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was another hot day in Honduras, when I set off from Puerto Cortes at 7 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was already displaying 33 degrees Celsius on my bike. I headed for the Guatemalan border that was about an hour away and as the road passed close to the coast I stopped to take a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/121-122/01-121.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On my arrival at the Honduran side of the border at 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, as usual I was stopped and asked for my passport. I was then allowed to proceed to the main border building. I had hoped that by arriving at the border early it would be relatively quiet. However, when I parked the bike I saw a huge queue of people standing at the Honduras exit window, apparently everyone else had the same idea as me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 119 to 120 Nicaragua to Honduras</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/119-120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/119-120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-119&#34;&gt;Day 119&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-119&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my stay in Managua I managed to obtain 2 new electrical relays for the bike which should now hopefully put an end to the starting issue I experienced a few days earlier. One other thing that I needed to attend to was that after my escapades with the punctures, when the bike was in the back of the truck full of sand, somehow or other a load of sand had gotten inside of my petrol tank via the filler cap. Thankfully it was in the overflow drain and not actually inside the tank with the petrol.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 117 to 118 Nicaragua Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/117-118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/117-118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-117&#34;&gt;Day 117&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-117&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So after another day in puncture city I was ready to continue my journey. I set off at 8 am and I was more than a little relieved that everything on the bike seemed to be working normally but it was not long until I reached the roadworks and the stretches of gravel roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/117-118/01-117.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I negotiated the roadworks with ease but I knew that as soon as I reached somewhere more urbanised I would have to obtain a couple of replacement relays to avoid any further starting issues. The two new tyres that I had gotten fitted to the bike are more suited for off road (gravel roads) than tarmac and because of this they caused the bike to squirm about more in corners than the previous ones, it took me a while to get used to the different handling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 116 Nicaragua Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-116&#34;&gt;Day 116&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-116&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up early and got ready to head off before 7 am as I knew that I had to contend with the unfinished road and the stone chip and gravel sections on my return from the coast. I left my hotel but as I was just about at the edge of town I got another puncture in my back tyre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/116/01-116.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So once again I got the back wheel off and the punctured tube out. I checked the tyre again but again I could find nothing that could have caused the puncture. I examined the tube and found a small cut to the centre of the tube meaning that whatever cut it was from the tyre side and not the wheel rim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 114 to 115 Nicaragua Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/114-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/114-115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-114&#34;&gt;Day 114&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-114&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I left Juigalpa it was a little overcast and just North of the town I stopped to take a photo of the mountains in the distance to the East.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/114-115/01-114.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I rode North along road 7 until the junction with road 198 where I then rode in the direction of the town of Comalapa however just as I turned on to the road I noticed that the road surface was made of paving bricks, the kind that are commonly used for driveways. The road was like this all the way to Comalapa and it was little odd to ride on such a long driveway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 112 to 113 Costa Rica to Nicaragua</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/112-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/112-113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-112&#34;&gt;Day 112&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-112&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst in San Marcos I stayed at a nice hotel which was a little expensive at $40 per night although breakfast was included in that price. However nice it was in San Marcos, I tend to get restless when I am off the bike for too long so on Monday 15th April I set off for the capital city, San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/112-113/01-112.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The road from San Marcos to San Jose wound up in to the mountains and provided some spectacular views and great riding but too soon it was over and I started to descend towards San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 110 to 111 Costa Rica</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/110--111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/110--111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-110&#34;&gt;Day 110&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-110&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent 3 nights at my accommodation in San Isidro and to be honest there was not much to do in the city and whilst I was there the weather started to turn showery which discouraged me from exploring further on the bike. I used my time to catch up on the usual housekeeping stuff like emails etc. and when eventually it was time to leave I have to say that I was glad to move on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 107 to 109 Panama to Costa Rica</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/107-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/107-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-107&#34;&gt;Day 107&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-107&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Panama city at just after 6 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning on Wednesday 3rd of April and my plan was to get to the city of David which lies about 35 miles West of the main border crossing between Panama and Costa Rica. The bike had just recorded 2,000 miles on the odometer the day before and the ride that day was just under 300 miles. The ride itself was pretty non eventful despite the 14 police speed traps that I passed all the way along Highway 1 during it. The 14 police speed traps that I passed were only the ones on the Westbound side of Highway 1, there were at least the same number if not more on the Eastbound side. I eventually arrived at my destination for the night in the city of David at around 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and I then spent a quite night contemplating whether or not I would be told when I eventually reached the border the following day, if I had the correct documents or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/seven-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;seven-years-down&#34;&gt;Seven Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#seven-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is now April 2024 and it has been 7 years since I left the UK to commence what I thought would be an around the world trip on my bike and my goodness how the world has changed!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2020 the world descended in to insanity and madness and, to me at least, it seems that no meaningful recovery to sanity has yet been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 104 to 106 Panama Part 4 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/104-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/104-106/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-104&#34;&gt;Day 104&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-104&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On leaving my jungle accommodation I had a short 20 or so mile ride to the border. On the way back to the main road I stopped at a bridge over the river and took a couple of photos of the crossing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/104-106/19-101.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/104-106/20-101.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I got near to the border I pulled in to a petrol station to refuel as I had heard that the price of petrol in Costa Rica is much more expensive that it is in Panama. I eventually reached the border crossing at 10 o’clock in the morning and riding up on to the bridge where the actual border crossing is located, I was stopped by two customs officers and two guys in camouflage uniforms with a drugs dog. After a short conversation I was told to go to the immigration building and then to go the customs building, in that order, which were in the town next to the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 103 Panama Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-103&#34;&gt;Day 103&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-103&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road to Boquette ends shortly after the Northern edge of the town and it is in effect a dead end, so to leave it there is no alternative but to retrace your steps back down Highway 41 in the direction of the city of David. So setting off South out of Boquette my plan was to head up to the Caribbean side of Panama and cross the border in to Costa Rica at the town of Guabito. Just out of Boquette I took Highway 10 to Gualaca and then headed North to the Caribbean coast. The road here was quite good except for the odd deep pothole or two and the views were also quite good of the volcano in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 101 to 103 Panama Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/101-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/101-102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-101&#34;&gt;Day 101&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-101&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a few days in Las Tablas I set off South on Highway 2 to explore the peninsula. I rode along the South coast of the peninsula and then I headed North to Macaracas and then on to Highway 50 where I eventually re-joined the main road, Highway 1. To be honest there was very little of interest to see in the peninsula except for signs of land being cleared for future developments, presumably to exploit the Southern coastline for tourists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 99 to 100 Panama Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/99-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/99-100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-99&#34;&gt;Day 99&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-99&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 11 February I headed off from the hotel in Panama city where I had been staying, North in the direction of Colon. In an earlier post I had visited Colon and found it not to my liking however, I was following a recommendation that I had received to visit the beaches to the East of the city. So as I approached the city I took a small road along the Caribbean coast to the East and headed for the town of Portobello where I had booked in to a hostel for 4 nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 2024 Out and About in Panama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/out-and-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/out-and-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rode the bike to the City of Colon on the Caribbean side of the isthmus of Panama to get some miles done to help the engine break in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/out-and-about/01-ri.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December 2023 Part Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:36:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/part-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;The Americas - Getting Started&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am now in Panama and I am preparing to continue my RTW trip from here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/part-two/01-ct.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have bought a new Himalayan from the local dealer here and as it only had 2 kilometres on the clock, I had to begin the process of breaking the engine in. So in real terms that means keeping the engine speeds below 3,000 RPM for the first 300 miles (500 km) which translates in to a top speed of 40 mph (60 kph)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/six-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;six-years-down&#34;&gt;Six Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#six-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I sit here in the city of Reus in Spain contemplating the choice of destination for continuing my RTW trip on my bike, I sometimes reflect on the six years that have passed since I permanently left the UK. When I think about my travels on my bike throughout Europe in those six years it seems only months ago that I started my journey, however, when I think about the madness that the world has descended in to since 2020 it seems like an eternity has passed and that nightmare will never end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 End of Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my RTW trip properly when I bought my Himalayan in August of 2019. Since then, just over 3 years later, I have visited every country in Europe that I wished to see and covered about 34,000 miles (57,600 km) doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/end-of-part-one/01-pt1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In covering those miles I have ridden for just 98 days of actual travelling, which averages out at around 350 miles (590 km) per day. 98 days of actual travelling in 3 years, not a lot!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 95 to 98 France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-95&#34;&gt;Day 95&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-95&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day it was sunny but cold. I rode for about 10 miles South from Tende on the D6204 and then took the D2204 to go over the Coll De Brouis. The road was fantastic and the views were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/01-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/02-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I stopped in the town of Sospel for coffee and croissants then once heated up by the morning sun I continued on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/03-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I continued riding on the D2204 and went over the Coll De Braus and Coll De Saint-Jean, again it continued to be a superb biking road with spectacular scenery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 91 to 94 Bosnia, Croatia, Slovenia and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-91&#34;&gt;Day 91&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-91&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I set off North from Sarajevo to Banja Luka which on arrival I found to be a very nondescript city, so deciding not to stop there, I then continued riding and headed West for the Croatian border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/01-92.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst the scenery in Bosnia was reasonably pleasant, like my time in Serbia, I found very little to hold my attention and like Serbia, it is not a country that I will return to. I crossed the border in to Croatia and I headed West to the coast. I stopped at the first reasonable sized town and I was able to get some Croatian money from an ATM. Luckily I had made better calculations than I had in Serbia so I had no Bosnian cash to try to get rid of, which was fortunate because yet again there were no money exchange facilities at the border crossing. A few weeks before setting off on the trip, I had encountered post in somewhere or other about a guy who ran a small operation hosting bikers in the spare rooms of his house, so having made contact with him I headed for his place. The guy used to run a motorbike shop in England and provided me with very comfortable accommodation for around 20 Euros a night. I stayed for 3 nights to get a bit of a break and to attend to an oil change and some minor tinkering here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 88 to 90 Albainia and Montenegro to Bosnia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-88&#34;&gt;Day 88&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-88&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once packed and on the road early the next morning, I headed in land for a bit before the road headed for the coast again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/01-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/02-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/03-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took the coastal road up to Vlore and this was again a stunning road to ride along. This road rose and fell continually and at one point from one decent vantage point I photographed Vlore from the roadside.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/04-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/05-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North of Vlore I followed the coast until I got to Tirana the capital city of Albania. This route in this part of the country I would not recommend as the roads were much busier and the countryside was pretty flat. In addition, most of the buildings that could be seen from the road were partly finished and partly a construction site. When I got to Tirana I booked a &amp;ldquo;Communist Style&amp;rdquo; room for about 20 Euros, however the name was merely a marketing ploy to attract gullible tourists (like myself on this occasion) to pay for an unrenovated room stuffed with old 1970&amp;rsquo;s furniture. To be fair it did however have some reproduction communist style electrical appliances so I suppose it fulfilled the description to some degree. Tirana was not what I had expected and much of the city was very modern. The main focal point of the city was a massive square where the opera is situated but there was little around it in the way of bars, cafes, or restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 85 to 87 North Macedonia to Albania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-85&#34;&gt;Day 85&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-85&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, after breakfast I headed West through the mountains in the direction of the Albanian border crossing at Lake Ohrid, however, as I was nearing the border I saw the dark clouds massing and just managed to get in to a petrol station before an enormous thunderstorm rolled in keeping me drinking coffee for nearly 2 hours until it passed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/01-85.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I eventually crossed the Albanian border it was late in the afternoon so my first task was to get a SIM card and cash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 Hungary and Serbia to North Macedonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is quite a well spread out city that is much longer East to West that in its from North to South. The city does not have a central square and this seems to be a thing in Slovakia, Hungary and other countries to the South of Europe, instead it has an elongated main street on which most of the shops, bars, and cafes are located. From my experiences it seems to me that central squares seem to be more prevalent in Northern European countries for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 79 to 81 Poland and Slovakia to Hungary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/79-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/79-81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-79&#34;&gt;Day 79&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-79&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world is still mad and borders are still shut because of the alleged virus, or wars, or other political nonsense, and all roads East from Central Europe are still closed. So, its on the merry go round once again and back to Spain to visit my friend. However, this time the Balkans are open for business (well apart from Kosovo and Serbia going at it again!) so I decided to take the opportunity to visit these countries whilst I can. Therefore on 15th August 2022 I headed South from Krakow and took the road from there to the Southern Polish city of Bielsko-Biala. I had never actually been here before so this was a perfect time for a visit and I found it to be quite surprising. The town was obviously fortified at some time and the nicer part of the town is to be found within these walls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Years Down And Who Would Have Guessed?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-years-down&#34;&gt;Five Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#five-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been five years since I left Scotland to begin my Round The World trip (RTW) and who would have guessed how the world would have so dramatically changed since April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years-down/01-fyd.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since leaving, I have travelled in excess of forty thousand miles on my bike(s) and yet I find myself still in Europe. The reasons for this are a combination of my own tardiness and the world shutting down in 2020. As I wait, hoping that I will soon be able to continue with my RTW trip, my thoughts about the dramatic changes that have taken place in the world over the past two years have made me wonder in what direction the world will now move because of those changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 Spain, France, Italy, Austria and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As those who read this blog are aware of my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engine Rebuild and Spain December 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rebuild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The damage to the bike engine was substantial so I knew that it would take more than a few days to fix it. As I have owned and ridden bikes continually since I was a teenager my acquired mechanical knowledge and abilities allow me to do all of my own bike maintenance. Fortunately these skills and knowledge also allow me to undertake major mechanical tasks such as the engine repair. The engine removal was straightforward enough and once out the rest of the bike was very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 Poland, Germany and France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years Down and the Tatra Mountains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:48:57 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has now been 4 years since I left the UK on my adventures, however, as I mentioned in my previous post because of all of the madness engendered in politicians in respect of restrictions on individual movement I am unable to travel much and I am presently marking time in Krakow in Poland. I just thought that I would post this update on my stalled RTW trip and to share a few photographs of my jaunts around Southern Poland in to the Tatra Mountains and around Krakow during the last few months of captivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 Romania, Hungary and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 65 to 67 Turkey, Bulgaria and Moldovian Border to Romania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-65&#34;&gt;Day 65&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-65&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for leaving Turkey was because all of the land routes to the East from Turkey were closed and because of this I had to decide where to go for the winter. Staying in Turkey was an option but having a 90 day limit to my stay would have meant having to leave Turkey at the end of January to go back a European country. Another factor for consideration was the potential for the alleged virus to affect border crossings at the end of January in to February. As the borders were still open at that time I decided that it would be better to make that journey in early November rather than at the beginning of February. I left Kırklareli early the next day and headed for the Bulgarian border. On approaching the border the road rose sharply and in the shaded parts, the road was covered in frost. A few minutes at the border and I was once again in Bulgaria. I rode along the coast past Burgas and Varna, I only stopped for fuel and coffee as it was not warming up and it had become overcast. I was at the Romanian border by late afternoon and once through I headed for the unremarkable city of Constanta where I spent the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 62 to 64 Turkey Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:39:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-62&#34;&gt;Day 62&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-62&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road to Antalya was very open and the route that I had chosen swept South down from the mountains&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/00-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/01-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and then along the shore of a large lake and eventually via some boring fast dual carriageway heading to the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/02-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/62-64/03-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did stop at the side of the road for a cup of tea and found that the resteraunt specialised in fish, you just had to pick which one that you wanted to eat!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aizanoi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aizanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 12:52:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aizanoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;The Greek/Roman City of Aizanoi&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site was one of the best and undeveloped sites that I have yet encountered on my travels. Apart from a partially complete temple, the site had row upon row of stone carvings that were used to decorate the many buildings that used to stand on this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most amazing things on this site was a complete underground vault that had survived from when it was originally constructed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 59 to 61 Turkey Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:19:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-59&#34;&gt;Day 59&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-59&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After out encounter with the wolves the previous night we decided that later that day we would spend a night in a hotel so we set off to head for the city of Eskisehir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/01-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As usual we took some smaller scenic routes and at a leisurely pace I was able to stop to take the odd photo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/02-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/03-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/59-61/04-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and then eventually we headed for our hotel in the city of Eskisehir.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 56 to 58 Turkey Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:19:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-56&#34;&gt;Day 56&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-56&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending 2 nights in the city we set off again up in to the mountains that sit to the south of the city and our first stop was to look at a tree which allegedly over 600 years old, it was certainly the biggest tree that I have ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/01-56.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/56-58/02-56.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then we rode up to the top of the mountain and to a viewpoint where we could see the enormous size of the city far below us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 53 to 55 Turkey Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 19:34:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-53&#34;&gt;Day 53&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-53&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/53--55/01-53.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the the Greek and Turkish border under a cloudy sky which looked like it could produce some rain. After the usual rounds of producing my passport and bike ownership documents to the Greek and Turkish border and customs officials, I was almost cleared to enter Turkey. However, I first had to go to one of the buildings at the border and purchase insurance that covered me for riding my bike in Turkey. For the price of about 15 Euros I obtained 90 days cover. Now I was in Turkey and I set off for Isatnbul. The rain was light and came and went and I was getting a bit bored and then I saw this at the side of the road. A Boeing 737 restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 47 to 52 Bulgaria and Greece to Turkish Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/47-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:23:31 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/47-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-47&#34;&gt;Day 47&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-47&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the madness I had to pre book my accommodation in Greece and pass the details to the Greek government before entry, therefore once I entered Greece I had to get from the border crossing to the port of Igoumenitsa on the West of Greece to cross over to the island of Corfu and because I was travelling a large distance to catch a ferry, a full day on the Greek motorways and an early start was required. It was still dark when I loaded up the bike and set off for the border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 46 Bulgaria to Greek Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:57:01 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-45&#34;&gt;Day 45&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-45&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 days off the bike I needed to get going again so I left Sofia in the pouring rain and headed South East in the direction of Plovdiv. My reasons for visiting Plovdiv were twofold, firstly I had read that this city was the oldest continually inhabited city in Europe and secondly, as I wanted to visit Greece, I needed to get tested for the alleged virus and a hospital in Plovdiv provided this service. I booked in to a modern hotel a short walk from the old town for 4 nights at about 30 Euros per night. While I waited on being tested I explored the city and found that the city had a lot of excavated Roman architecture still visible in the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 43 to 44 Romanaia to Bulgaria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-43&#34;&gt;Day 43&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-43&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day when I arrived at the Bulgarian border it was pretty quiet and there were just a couple of cars in the queue in front of me but then I encountered one of the most common road defects that Central and East Europe has to offer, &amp;ldquo;Tramlines&amp;rdquo;. These are the large longitudinal indentations left in the road surface by the repeated driving on hot, soft, tarmac by very heavy lorries. Unfortunately, they change the camber of the road and whilst waiting in line to be seen by the Romanian authorities and sitting astride my bike in one of these &amp;ldquo;tramlines&amp;rdquo;, I dropped my passport. My passport landed on the road to the right of the bike just out of my reach, so I put the bike of the side stand and dismounted to retrieve it. As I picked it up I heard the sickening crunch of my bike hitting the road. A combination of the bike sitting in the &amp;ldquo;tramline&amp;rdquo;, the side stand resting on an adverse camber, and a strong gust of wind caused the bike to fall over, bending the brake lever in the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 39 to 42 Slovakia and Hungary to Romanaia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-39&#34;&gt;Day 39&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I head off South from my hotel in Kompachy in the direction of Hungary and at about 12 noon I get to a small border crossing, as expected there is no one on the Slovakian side but I am surprised to see that there are two guards carrying AK47&amp;rsquo;s on the Hungarian side. As I drive towards them I get stopped by the guards and they ask for my passport. They give it back to me and then hand me a form that they have just filled out. As I do not read Hungarian I ask what it is and they tell me it is permission to enter and leave the country so I put it in my passport, thank them and ride on to Budapest where I had booked accommodation for two nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 34 to 38 Poland, Lithuania and Ukrainian Border to Slovakia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 18:39:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-34&#34;&gt;Day 34&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-34&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I had finished with my coaching I resumed my travels and I headed North to Warsaw. I stayed in a small hotel on the edge of Warsaw for under 30 Euros and I was able to take the metro in to the city centre which I walked about in for a while, I also found that the old town was somewhat touristy but nonetheless quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/01-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/02-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/03-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-35&#34;&gt;Day 35&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-35&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off to do another favour for another friend. I had been told by my fiend that her father had escaped Poland as a boy in the aftermath of WW2 and had then settled in the USA. She had asked me to swing by the village that her father had been born in near to Byzgoszcz and take some photographs for her. Once this mission had been accomplished I headed North to Gdansk where I spent the night in a cheery hostel full of odd characters for under 20 Euros.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I crossed the border in to the Czech Republic in the rain and rode across to the other side of the county but all the while it continued to rain intermittently. I only stopped for petrol and then moved on trying to get to my destination for that day, the city of Brno as quickly as I could. As I arrived in Brno I got caught in a huge thunderstorm and I got thoroughly soaked before reaching my accommodation for the night. Once sorted out, as the rain had passed I walked in to Brno old town and I found it to be quite pleasant, however, the walk in was not quite as nice. There were lots of people hanging around street corners in large groups, mostly men in the twenties and although they never hassled me, I felt a certain tension in the air. In addition, the streets where these groups were congregating were full of litter and graffiti covered almost every wall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 France, Italy, Switzerland and Lichtenstein to Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28 Spain and Andora to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:49:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-28&#34;&gt;Day 28&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends is always good but leaves a sour taste when it comes time to say goodbye. This occasion was no different. So after a few days rest and relaxation I headed North on the C14 from Reus and made for the Pyrenees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/28/01-28.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riding a bike in the Pyrenees in the summer is a great experience, well surfaced twisty roads, great views and lots of great coffee stops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 24 to 27 Portugal to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:55:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-24&#34;&gt;Day 24&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After saying my goodbyes to my friends in Alvor I headed West. Riding along the N125 I passed by Faro and continued until I had to join the motorway to cross the border in to Spain. I then continued on the A49 from the border, circumventing Seville and headed South on the N4 and A381 till I eventually reached Gibraltar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/01-24.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once there I was disappointed as it was nothing like I had expected it to be and the only positive thing that I have to say about Gibraltar was the price of petrol at only 85 cents per litre. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what I was expecting but it seemed very cluttered, almost industrial in nature, so after a quick circuit it was back across the border and back in to Spain where I found a reasonable motel room for under 25 Euros for the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bike Repairs in Portugal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rocker-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 09:16:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rocker-cover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;Leaky Rocker Cover&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Alvor at the home of my friend and her husband to spend a few days catching up but the bike had developed a slight oil leak from the rocker/cylinder head cover so I spent the next few days attending to that. The removal was pretty straightforward except for the removal of the camshaft end plate, it was stuck solid with gasket sealant. However, once I finally got if off without damaging it, the removal of the old gasket sealant was pretty straightforward. I used ethanol and a small plastic scourer, the type they sell in multi-packs in every supermarket, and with a bit of time and effort both mating surfaces were cleaned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 20 to 23 Spain to Portugal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-20&#34;&gt;Day 20&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well with the best of intentions I arrived at my friends house in Galicia in late February 2020. Then suddenly, like almost every other place on the plant, I was unable to travel due to the alleged pandemic. As news of borders re-opening and travel being permitted once again started to circulate, I got the bike ready to move. I fitted new Mitas E-07 tires, carried out an oil and filter change, the engine tappets and the wheel spokes were adjusted as required, a new touring seat purchased and fitted, the brake fluid was changed and both callipers cleaned and greased. I got a set of custom made side plates to stop my soft throwover panniers tucking in on the back wheel and because of the broken rear indicator stem that I picked up when an old man in a car side swiped me in Italy the previous year, I got indicator protectors built in to the plates and once these were fitted the bike was good to go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Covid Lockdowns and Three Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-madness-begins&#34;&gt;The Madness Begins&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-madness-begins&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;About a week or so after I arrived at my friend&amp;rsquo;s home in Galcia I started to hear media reports of an outbreak of the Covid 19 virus in the Cremona area of Northern Italy where a large number of people were apparently getting very ill and or dying, apparently as a result of being infected by this virus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I realised that I had passed through the epicentre of the Italian outbreak two days before I had my bout of fever, I looked up some of the known symptoms etc. pertaining to this virus. Lo and behold an incubation period of two days and one of the lesser symptoms was fever and or shivers. However all I had was one night of fever and if one cares to look at fever as a symptom, the list of &amp;ldquo;diseases&amp;rdquo; that this can be attributed to is almost endless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 17 to 19 France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:13:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-17&#34;&gt;Day 17&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days with a friend in Aix En Provence I said my goodbyes to him and headed for the Spanish border. Leaving Aix En Provence I headed West on the D7N, D572 and D6572 to Montpellier. The journey was pleasant enough in the early morning sun but these roads were too urbanised for my liking so, after circumventing Montpellier I took a short trip West on the A750 motorway until I found the D908 that headed West through the Languedoc National park area. This was a stunning road to ride in the warm early afternoon sunshine. Lots of beautiful scenery, very few cars on the road and the odd picturesque village to stop in and admire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 Poland, Slovakia, Austria and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the actions of an asshole, my time in Krakow was obviously at an end and it was decision time. Either to leave or to assault the asshole. So early one February morning I packed the bike and got ready to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 France, Italy, Switzerland, Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things that I have noticed during my riding through France is that the road numbers can suddenly change without warning. For example the D133 that I started on changed mysteriously after about 10 miles and became the D541. Unless one keeps a close eye on this it can get very confusing. Yes, I know a Sat Nav would make this point irrelevant but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I like to travel. Riding further East towards Gap I could see the mountains start to rise in the distance. It had been several years since I had ridden over any Alpine passes and I was looking forward to it but by now the sun was strong, it was very warm, and the scenery forced me to stop, not only to capture its beauty and grandeur but also to pause and soak it all up over a cup of coffee or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 6 to 8 Spain to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:17:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lounging about in the sun and riding some forest dirt roads in Galicia to reacquaint myself with riding off road it was time to head back to Krakow in Poland where I planned to spend the Winter. After saying my goodbyes in Galicia I set off for the East coast of Spain. I took the N120 from Monforete De lemos to Ponferrada and although this is a fast main road it is quite pleasant to ride on with a bike as it twists and turns as it climbs up the valley of the river Sil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 United Kingdom to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leaving Folkestone I boarded the train that travels under the English channel to France. I have done this a few times before and as usual I met some fellow two wheeled travellers on board. After 20 minutes or so of exchanging stories and thoughts about each other&amp;rsquo;s bikes, I said my farewells and rode South from Calais towards the city of Tours that would be my first stop on my way to Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 1 to 2 United Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 11:42:00 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my newly purchased Royal Enfield Himalayan I left Folkestone to ride the 500 miles or so to Glasgow on the motorways on the East coast of England. Riding this new bike was strange after having powerful large capacity sports touring bikes for the past 20 or so of my life. The Kawasaki ZZR1200 that I had just part-exchanged for the Himalayan produced around 160 brake horse power (BHP) and was restricted to a top speed of 186 mph (290 kph). This bike only produced 24 BHP and I was still to discover what spped it was capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain 2019 and Two Years Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-2019--two-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:40:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-2019--two-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.. the story so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left the city of Reus in in December 2018 for the home of my good friend in Galicia, with only a vague idea about what I wanted to do next. En route I decided to visit the city of Leon, a city that I had always wanted to see but had never actually gotten around to visiting. Leon lived up to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-2019--two-years/01-spain.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-2019--two-years/02-spain.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-2019--two-years/03-spain.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent a night in a hotel that was not only a hotel but also a museum and one of the oldest buildings in that part of Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:48:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in the city of Opole about a month ago and I must say that of the little of Poland that I have seen, I like this country. In places Poland reminds me of Scotland as it used to be about 40 years ago and in other places it looks just like any other modern European country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-2018/01-pol.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that there is very little money floating around this part of Poland, probably why so many Polish people travel to the UK and Germany to find better paid employment, and this is why some parts of this country remind me of Scotland during the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:40:22 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it was 1 year ago that I left Scotland behind to make my journey around the world and I arrived in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from my earlier posts, I decided to stay in Spain for 2 years to learn the language as I knew that it would be an invaluable asset on my journey around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what has the 1st year of my journey been like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Break in the Country</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 09:10:42 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is nothing better to lift the spirits than a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, in the middle of July I took the bike out and rode it 1000 km to my friend&amp;rsquo;s house in Galicia. Not a cloud in the sky, 40 degrees and the whole journey I managed to do in (Ahem!) hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only problem I encountered was at about 995 km in to the journey, as I was approaching the cut off for the village where my friend lives, I felt a sharp pain in my back and suddenly more pain, and then again. Having had this pain on a number of occasions before whilst travelling on a bike in the summer, I realised that a wasp had managed to get inside my jacket and was now stinging me but as I was travelling at (Ahem!) mph there was little I could do about it, so it continued to sting me until I reached my friends house. Once there I quickly shed my jacket and when it fell out I stamped the wasp to death. I know I should not have killed it but I needed to do it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At The Zoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/at-the-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 19:33:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/at-the-zoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On arriving in Reus I spent my first uneventful week in the city at a local hotel and I, with some local assistance, attempted to find a suitable place to rent. However, as I was soon to learn, nothing happens quickly in Spain and by the time my check out date was fast approaching I was still no further forward. As the hotel was fully booked for the next week I managed to secure a holiday apartment for two weeks just between the holiday towns of Salou and Cambrils.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unshackled Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-unshackled-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-unshackled-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once I had spent a relaxing night in Santiago de Compostella I boarded a train to the town of Monforte de Lemos which is near to the village where my good friend stays. I had purchased a ticket on-line (in Spanish) the previous evening and on boarding the train I found that my Spanish was not as good as I had hoped.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the ticket price was 24 Euros for the 70 odd mile journey I had assumed that it was a standard fare but when I took my numbered seat I was quickly ejected from it by an elderly Spanish woman who thrust her ticket under my nose whilst at the same time shouting loudly and pointing at me. Surely the train company had not issued two tickets for the same seat?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over The Finish Line</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 18:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/over-the-finish-line/01-sant.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once my house had eventually been sold it was time for me to leave the UK for good. I hired a car, said my farewells and drove off to England for a few days to do likewise with my friends South of the border. A few days later I was on a plane heading for the next part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plane that I was on had departed from Stanstead airport a few hours earlier but as it was approaching Santiago airport in the North West of Spain my vice-like grip on my seat began to loosen. Ever since as a young police officer I attended the crash site of flight Pan Am 103 that was blown out of the sky over the town of Lockerbie in Southern Scotland one evening in December 1988, I have, for obvious reasons, always disliked flying. As the wheels of the plane touched the runway, and much to the consternation of the somewhat refined middle class English woman sitting next to me I burst out laughing. Due to what I have previously written here of my dislike of flying, you would assume that it was some sort of reaction to a sudden release of tension and apparently so did the woman next to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:25:03 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Northwest of Spain where my friend lives reminds me of Scotland, it is a place full of mountains, tree covered slopes, and deep dark bodies of water. Like Scotland for about two or three months of the year it is cold, it is cloudy, and it rains a lot but this is where the similarities end as for the rest of the year it is sunny and warm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-two/01-gal.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the winter months, largely due to the amount of water in this area, a ground frost or mist usually lingers till about 10 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning until the sun disposes of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Another Rant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 12:56:45 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing--rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have updated this blog, a lot has happened to me since my last post so I shall start where I left off. After leaving my bike at the home of my friend in Galicia I flew back to the UK and arrived a Stanstead airport only to find that my flight to Glasgow was delayed by a couple of hours by snow on the runways, however eventually the plane took off and I was Scotland bound once again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:17:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I departed the UK on 14 December 2016 astride my bike sort of as planned (more on this later) and yes it did feel as good as I thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a cold but uneventful 500 mile journey I arrived at Folkestone to drive on to the train that would take me out of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/01-bike.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above picture, you just drive up, wait a few minutes and then drive on to the train, and 20 or so minutes later you are in France. Once in France i found my way to my hotel in Calais and settled down for the night. The following day a long, but cold, 500 mile trip through the motorways of central France saw me safely tucked up in a very bohemian hotel in the town of Milau. You can say what you like about the French, you may like them or loath them but undeniably they have their own very definite sense of fashion and style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Cluttering of a Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 09:11:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent dismantling of my present life in preparation for the next part of my life I have found to be an unexpectedly cathartic experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The de-cluttering of a life is something I can now definitely recommend and whether the de-cluttering is solely of unused physical possessions or otherwise is up to you, but it is a process that for me has prompted a realisation that it is perhaps something that I should have done a long time ago. I was surprised at the quantity of items that I possessed for which I had no real use. I may have had a use for them at one time in my life but there they sat in the cupboard, loft, or drawer willing me to hang on to them for just another year, just in case….&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons For Departure...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 11:33:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-for-departue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fully expected that the next post that I made in this blog would be something to do with my bike and how it is now serviced and ready to hurtle off towards the setting sun&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However one of the many reasons as to why I have taken a dislike to this country has just sneaked up and prodded me in the eye. I should know better by now but against my better judgement I had a quick look at the evening news as hosted by the BBC (Biased Broadcasting Corporation) only to be informed that as a result of BREXIT, inflation is on the rise and prices of goods including petrol are expected to rise as a result. I get that, with a weaker pound imported products will cost more, but petrol?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost at the finishing line for the last time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another cold winter in Scotland and retirement is almost upon me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/02-snow.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tried it once before but circumstances outwith my control forced me to get back on to the hamster wheel. However there is nothing quite like having a pointless job to sharpen the desire to leave it. Finally after 5 long years of mind numbing trivia crushing my soul I can finally get off the hamster wheel for good and find something useful or worthwhile to do with the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
