<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 123 to 124 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-123&#34;&gt;Day 123&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-123&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my accommodation in Coban at just after 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and set off for the city of Huehuetenango which I had decided to ride to that day. Google maps showed that Huehuetenango was just over 120 miles away but the time to do it was show as nearly 5 hours so I knew to expect some slow going in parts of my journey for the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as I left Coban I saw a really nice roadside restaurant so I pulled in for coffee and breakfast, steak with scrambled eggs for 35 Quetzals (4.50 US Dollars)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/01-123.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 121 to 122 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-121&#34;&gt;Day 121&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-121&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was another hot day in Honduras, when I set off from Puerto Cortes at 7 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was already displaying 33 degrees Celsius on my bike. I headed for the Guatemalan border that was about an hour away and as the road passed close to the coast I stopped to take a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/01-121.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 119 to 120 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-119&#34;&gt;Day 119&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-119&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my stay in Managua I managed to obtain 2 new electrical relays for the bike which should now hopefully put an end to the starting issue I experienced a few days earlier. One other thing that I needed to attend to was that after my escapades with the punctures, when the bike was in the back of the truck full of sand, somehow or other a load of sand had gotten inside of my petrol tank via the filler cap. Thankfully it was in the overflow drain and not actually inside the tank with the petrol.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/01-120.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 117 to 118 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-117&#34;&gt;Day 117&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-117&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So after another day in puncture city I was ready to continue my journey. I set off at 8 am and I was more than a little relieved that everything on the bike seemed to be working normally but it was not long until I reached the roadworks and the stretches of gravel roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/01-117.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 116 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-116&#34;&gt;Day 116&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-116&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up early and got ready to head off before 7 am as I knew that I had to contend with the unfinished road and the stone chip and gravel sections on my return from the coast. I left my hotel but as I was just about at the edge of town I got another puncture in my back tyre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/01-116.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 114 to 115 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-114&#34;&gt;Day 114&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-114&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I left Juigalpa it was a little overcast and just North of the town I stopped to take a photo of the mountains in the distance to the East.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/01-114.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 112 to 113 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-112&#34;&gt;Day 112&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-112&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst in San Marcos I stayed at a nice hotel which was a little expensive at $40 per night although breakfast was included in that price. However nice it was in San Marcos, I tend to get restless when I am off the bike for too long so on Monday 15th April I set off for the capital city, San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/01-112.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 110 to 111 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-110&#34;&gt;Day 110&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-110&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent 3 nights at my accommodation in San Isidro and to be honest there was not much to do in the city and whilst I was there the weather started to turn showery which discouraged me from exploring further on the bike. I used my time to catch up on the usual housekeeping stuff like emails etc. and when eventually it was time to leave I have to say that I was glad to move on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left San Isidro in the direction of San Jose (the capital city of Costa Rica) and immediately the road started to climb, and climb. In total the road climbed up in to the mountains for about 30 miles before it levelled off a bit and by this time I was high enough in the mountains to be above some clouds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/02-110.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 107 to 109 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/107-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/107-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-107&#34;&gt;Day 107&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-107&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Panama city at just after 6 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning on Wednesday 3rd of April and my plan was to get to the city of David which lies about 35 miles West of the main border crossing between Panama and Costa Rica. The bike had just recorded 2,000 miles on the odometer the day before and the ride that day was just under 300 miles. The ride itself was pretty non eventful despite the 14 police speed traps that I passed all the way along Highway 1 during it. The 14 police speed traps that I passed were only the ones on the Westbound side of Highway 1, there were at least the same number if not more on the Eastbound side. I eventually arrived at my destination for the night in the city of David at around 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and I then spent a quite night contemplating whether or not I would be told when I eventually reached the border the following day, if I had the correct documents or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/seven-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/seven-years-down/</guid>
      <description>Seven Years DownIt is now April 2024 and it has been 7 years since I left the UK to commence what I thought would be an around the world trip on my bike and my goodness how the world has changed!&#xA;At the beginning of 2020 the world descended in to insanity and madness and, to me at least, it seems that no meaningful recovery to sanity has yet been achieved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 104 to 106 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/104-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/104-106/</guid>
      <description>Day 104On leaving my jungle accommodation I had a short 20 or so mile ride to the border. On the way back to the main road I stopped at a bridge over the river and took a couple of photos of the crossing.&#xA;As I got near to the border I pulled in to a petrol station to refuel as I had heard that the price of petrol in Costa Rica is much more expensive that it is in Panama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 103 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/103/</guid>
      <description>Day 103The road to Boquette ends shortly after the Northern edge of the town and it is in effect a dead end, so to leave it there is no alternative but to retrace your steps back down Highway 41 in the direction of the city of David. So setting off South out of Boquette my plan was to head up to the Caribbean side of Panama and cross the border in to Costa Rica at the town of Guabito.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 101 to 103 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/101-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/101-102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-101&#34;&gt;Day 101&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-101&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a few days in Las Tablas I set off South on Highway 2 to explore the peninsula. I rode along the South coast of the peninsula and then I headed North to Macaracas and then on to Highway 50 where I eventually re-joined the main road, Highway 1. To be honest there was very little of interest to see in the peninsula except for signs of land being cleared for future developments, presumably to exploit the Southern coastline for tourists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I then headed West for Santiago where I spent the night at a hotel by the side of the main road about 10 miles East of the city for about $30. It was a nice enough place but there was nothing near to the hotel which had no restaurant. Another downside to this hotel was that during the night there was a lot of noise and serious vibrations from the passing lorries that thundered along taking advantage of the deserted road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 99 to 100 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/99-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/99-100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-99&#34;&gt;Day 99&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-99&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 11 February I headed off from the hotel in Panama city where I had been staying, North in the direction of Colon. In an earlier post I had visited Colon and found it not to my liking however, I was following a recommendation that I had received to visit the beaches to the East of the city. So as I approached the city I took a small road along the Caribbean coast to the East and headed for the town of Portobello where I had booked in to a hostel for 4 nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 2024 Out and About in Panama</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rode the bike to the City of Colon on the Caribbean side of the isthmus of Panama to get some miles done to help the engine break in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/01-ri.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December 2023 Part Two</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:36:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;The Americas - Getting Started&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am now in Panama and I am preparing to continue my RTW trip from here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/01-ct.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have bought a new Himalayan from the local dealer here and as it only had 2 kilometres on the clock, I had to begin the process of breaking the engine in. So in real terms that means keeping the engine speeds below 3,000 RPM for the first 300 miles (500 km) which translates in to a top speed of 40 mph (60 kph)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/six-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/six-years-down/</guid>
      <description>Six Years DownAs I sit here in the city of Reus in Spain contemplating the choice of destination for continuing my RTW trip on my bike, I sometimes reflect on the six years that have passed since I permanently left the UK. When I think about my travels on my bike throughout Europe in those six years it seems only months ago that I started my journey, however, when I think about the madness that the world has descended in to since 2020 it seems like an eternity has passed and that nightmare will never end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 End of Part One</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/end-of-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/end-of-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my RTW trip properly when I bought my Himalayan in August of 2019. Since then, just over 3 years later, I have visited every country in Europe that I wished to see and covered about 34,000 miles (57,600 km) doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/end-of-part-one/01-pt1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 95 to 98 September 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-95&#34;&gt;Day 95&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-95&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day it was sunny but cold. I rode for about 10 miles South from Tende on the D6204 and then took the D2204 to go over the Coll De Brouis. The road was fantastic and the views were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/95-98/01-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 91 to 94 September 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/91-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/91-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-91&#34;&gt;Day 91&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-91&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I set off North from Sarajevo to Banja Luka which on arrival I found to be a very nondescript city, so deciding not to stop there, I then continued riding and headed West for the Croatian border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/91-94/01-92.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 88 to 90 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/88-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/88-90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-88&#34;&gt;Day 88&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-88&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once packed and on the road early the next morning, I headed in land for a bit before the road headed for the coast again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/88-90/01-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 85 to 87 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/85-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/85-87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-85&#34;&gt;Day 85&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-85&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, after breakfast I headed West through the mountains in the direction of the Albanian border crossing at Lake Ohrid, however, as I was nearing the border I saw the dark clouds massing and just managed to get in to a petrol station before an enormous thunderstorm rolled in keeping me drinking coffee for nearly 2 hours until it passed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/85-87/01-85.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 79 to 81 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-79&#34;&gt;Day 79&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-79&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world is still mad and borders are still shut because of the alleged virus, or wars, or other political nonsense, and all roads East from Central Europe are still closed. So, its on the merry go round once again and back to Spain to visit my friend. However, this time the Balkans are open for business (well apart from Kosovo and Serbia going at it again!) so I decided to take the opportunity to visit these countries whilst I can. Therefore on 15th August 2022 I headed South from Krakow and took the road from there to the Southern Polish city of Bielsko-Biala. I had never actually been here before so this was a perfect time for a visit and I found it to be quite surprising. The town was obviously fortified at some time and the nicer part of the town is to be found within these walls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/01-79.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Years Down And Who Would Have Guessed?</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/five-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/five-years-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-years-down&#34;&gt;Five Years Down&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#five-years-down&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been five years since I left Scotland to begin my Round The World trip (RTW) and who would have guessed how the world would have so dramatically changed since April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/five-years-down/01-fyd.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 January 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you are all aware my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engine Rebuild and Spain December 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The damage to the bike engine was substantial so I knew that it would take more than a few days to fix it. As I have owned and ridden bikes continually since I was a teenager my acquired mechanical knowledge and abilities allow me to do all of my own bike maintenance. Fortunately these skills and knowledge also allow me to undertake major mechanical tasks such as the engine repair. The engine removal was straightforward enough and once out the rest of the bike was very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rebuild/01-rb.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 August 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years Down and the Tatra Mountains</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:48:57 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has now been 4 years since I left the UK on my adventures, however, as I mentioned in my previous post because of all of the madness engendered in politicians in respect of restrictions on individual movement I am unable to travel much and I am presently marking time in Krakow in Poland. I just thought that I would post this update on my stalled RTW trip and to share a few photographs of my jaunts around Southern Poland in to the Tatra Mountains and around Krakow during the last few months of captivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Krynica Area of Southern Poland&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/four-years-down-tatra-mountains/01-tm.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 65 to 67 November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/65-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/65-67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-65&#34;&gt;Day 65&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-65&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for leaving Turkey was because all of the land routes to the East from Turkey were closed and because of this I had to decide where to go for the winter. Staying in Turkey was an option but having a 90 day limit to my stay would have meant having to leave Turkey at the end of January to go back a European country. Another factor for consideration was the potential for the alleged virus to affect border crossings at the end of January in to February. As the borders were still open at that time I decided that it would be better to make that journey in early November rather than at the beginning of February. I left Kırklareli early the next day and headed for the Bulgarian border. On approaching the border the road rose sharply and in the shaded parts, the road was covered in frost. A few minutes at the border and I was once again in Bulgaria. I rode along the coast past Burgas and Varna, I only stopped for fuel and coffee as it was not warming up and it had become overcast. I was at the Romanian border by late afternoon and once through I headed for the unremarkable city of Constanta where I spent the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 62 to 64 November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/62-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:39:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/62-64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-62&#34;&gt;Day 62&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-62&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road to Antalya was very open and the route that I had chosen swept South down from the mountains&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/62-64/00-62.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aizanoi</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/aizanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 12:52:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/aizanoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;The Greek/Roman City of Aizanoi&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-greekroman-city-of-aizanoi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site was one of the best and undeveloped sites that I have yet encountered on my travels. Apart from a partially complete temple, the site had row upon row of stone carvings that were used to decorate the many buildings that used to stand on this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most amazing things on this site was a complete underground vault that had survived from when it was originally constructed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/aizanoi/01-az.JPG&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 59 to 61 October 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/59-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:19:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/59-61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-59&#34;&gt;Day 59&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-59&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After out encounter with the wolves the previous night we decided that later that day we would spend a night in a hotel so we set off to head for the city of Eskisehir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/59-61/01-59.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 56 to 58 October 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/56-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:19:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/56-58/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-56&#34;&gt;Day 56&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-56&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending 2 nights in the city we set off again up in to the mountains that sit to the south of the city and our first stop was to look at a tree which allegedly over 600 years old, it was certainly the biggest tree that I have ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/56-58/01-56.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 53 to 55 October 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/53--55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 19:34:26 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/53--55/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-53&#34;&gt;Day 53&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-53&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/53--55/01-53.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 47 to 52 October 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/47-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:23:31 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/47-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-47&#34;&gt;Day 47&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-47&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the madness I had to pre book my accommodation in Greece and pass the details to the Greek government before entry, therefore once I entered Greece I had to get from the border crossing to the port of Igoumenitsa on the West of Greece to cross over to the island of Corfu and because I was travelling a large distance to catch a ferry, a full day on the Greek motorways and an early start was required. It was still dark when I loaded up the bike and set off for the border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 46 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/45-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:57:01 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/45-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-45&#34;&gt;Day 45&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-45&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 days off the bike I needed to get going again so I left Sofia in the pouring rain and headed South East in the direction of Plovdiv. My reasons for visiting Plovdiv were twofold, firstly I had read that this city was the oldest continually inhabited city in Europe and secondly, as I wanted to visit Greece, I needed to get tested for the alleged virus and a hospital in Plovdiv provided this service. I booked in to a modern hotel a short walk from the old town for 4 nights at about 30 Euros per night. While I waited on being tested I explored the city and found that the city had a lot of excavated Roman architecture still visible in the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/45-46/01-45.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 43 to 44 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/43-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/43-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-43&#34;&gt;Day 43&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-43&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day when I arrived at the Bulgarian border it was pretty quiet and there were just a couple of cars in the queue in front of me but then I encountered one of the most common road defects that Central and East Europe has to offer, &amp;ldquo;Tramlines&amp;rdquo;. These are the large longitudinal indentations left in the road surface by the repeated driving on hot, soft, tarmac by very heavy lorries. Unfortunately, they change the camber of the road and whilst waiting in line to be seen by the Romanian authorities and sitting astride my bike in one of these &amp;ldquo;tramlines&amp;rdquo;, I dropped my passport. My passport landed on the road to the right of the bike just out of my reach, so I put the bike of the side stand and dismounted to retrieve it. As I picked it up I heard the sickening crunch of my bike hitting the road. A combination of the bike sitting in the &amp;ldquo;tramline&amp;rdquo;, the side stand resting on an adverse camber, and a strong gust of wind caused the bike to fall over, bending the brake lever in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, a few minutes later, passport and bike documents checked, I was in Bulgaria and changing my Romanian currency for Bulgarian currency. I stopped and grabbed a coffee and a cigar and as I sat drinking my coffee I realised that I was fatigued and needed to take a few day off from riding the bike. So I made a decision then and there to find some place relatively close to the border and take a break from riding for a few days. I found a small studio flat overlooking the Black sea just North of the city of Varna for about 14 Euros per night, so I decided to rest there for a while. This was the view from my balcony and of the nearby beach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/43-44/01-43.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 39 to 42 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-39&#34;&gt;Day 39&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I head off South from my hotel in Kompachy in the direction of Hungary and at about 12 noon I get to a small border crossing, as expected there is no one on the Slovakian side but I am surprised to see that there are two guards carrying AK47&amp;rsquo;s on the Hungarian side. As I drive towards them I get stopped by the guards and they ask for my passport. They give it back to me and then hand me a form that they have just filled out. As I do not read Hungarian I ask what it is and they tell me it is permission to enter and leave the country so I put it in my passport, thank them and ride on to Budapest where I had booked accommodation for two nights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/01-39.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 34 to 38 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 18:39:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-34&#34;&gt;Day 34&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-34&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I had finished with my coaching I resumed my travels and I headed North to Warsaw. I stayed in a small hotel on the edge of Warsaw for under 30 Euros and I was able to take the metro in to the city centre which I walked about in for a while, I also found that the old town was somewhat touristy but nonetheless quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/34-38/01-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 August 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/29-31/01-29.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:49:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-28&#34;&gt;Day 28&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends is always good but leaves a sour taste when it comes time to say goodbye. This occasion was no different. So after a few days rest and relaxation I headed North on the C14 from Reus and made for the Pyrenees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/28/01-28.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 24 to 27 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:55:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-24&#34;&gt;Day 24&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After saying my goodbyes to my friends in Alvor I headed West. Riding along the N125 I passed by Faro and continued until I had to join the motorway to cross the border in to Spain. I then continued on the A49 from the border, circumventing Seville and headed South on the N4 and A381 till I eventually reached Gibraltar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/24-27/01-24.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bike Repairs in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rocker-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 09:16:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rocker-cover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;Leaky Rocker Cover&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Alvor at the home of my friend and her husband to spend a few days catching up but the bike had developed a slight oil leak from the rocker/cylinder head cover so I spent the next few days attending to that. The removal was pretty straightforward except for the removal of the camshaft end plate, it was stuck solid with gasket sealant. However, once I finally got if off without damaging it, the removal of the old gasket sealant was pretty straightforward. I used ethanol and a small plastic scourer, the type they sell in multi-packs in every supermarket, and with a bit of time and effort both mating surfaces were cleaned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/rocker-cover/01-jane.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 20 to 23 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-20&#34;&gt;Day 20&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well with the best of intentions I arrived at my friends house in Galicia in late February. Then suddenly, like almost every other place on the plant, I was unable to travel due to the alleged pandemic. As news of borders re-opening and travel being permitted once again started to circulate, I got the bike ready to move. I fitted new Mitas E-07 tires, carried out an oil and filter change, the engine tappets and the wheel spokes were adjusted as required, a new touring seat purchased and fitted, the brake fluid was changed and both calipers cleaned and greased. I got a set of custom made side plates to stop my soft throwover panniers tucking in on the back wheel and because of the broken rear indicator stem that I picked up when an old man in a car side swiped me in Italy the previous year, I got indicator protectors built in to the plates and once these were fitted the bike was good to go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/20-23/01-20.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Covid Lockdowns and Three Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/three-years-lockdowns/</guid>
      <description>The Madness BeginsAbout a week or so after I arrived at my friend&amp;rsquo;s home in Galcia I started to hear media reports of an outbreak of the Covid 19 virus in the Cremona area of Northern Italy where a large number of people were apparently getting very ill and or dying, apparently as a result of being infected by this virus.&#xA;Once I realised that I had passed through the epicentre of the Italian outbreak two days before I had my bout of fever, I looked up some of the known symptoms etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 17 to 19 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:13:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-17&#34;&gt;Day 17&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days with a friend in Aix En Provence I said my goodbyes to him and headed for the Spanish border. Leaving Aix En Provence I headed West on the D7N, D572 and D6572 to Montpellier. The journey was pleasant enough in the early morning sun but these roads were too urbanised for my liking so, after circumventing Montpellier I took a short trip West on the A750 motorway until I found the D908 that headed West through the Languedoc National park area. This was a stunning road to ride in the warm early afternoon sunshine. Lots of beautiful scenery, very few cars on the road and the odd picturesque village to stop in and admire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/17-19/01-17.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 September 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 6 to 8 September 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:17:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lounging about in the sun and riding some forest dirt roads in Galicia to reacquaint myself with riding off road it was time to head back to Krakow in Poland where I planned to spend the Winter. After saying my goodbyes in Galicia I set off for the East coast of Spain. I took the N120 from Monforete De lemos to Ponferrada and although this is a fast main road it is quite pleasant to ride on with a bike as it twists and turns as it climbs up the valley of the river Sil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/6-8/01-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 August 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 1 to 2 August 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 11:42:00 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my newly purchased Royal Enfield Himalayan I left Folkestone to ride the 500 miles or so to Glasgow on the motorways on the East coast of England. Riding this new bike was strange after having powerful large capacity sports touring bikes for the past 20 or so of my life. The Kawasaki ZZR1200 that I had just part-exchanged for the Himalayan produced around 160 brake horse power (BHP) and was restricted to a top speed of 186 mph (290 kph). This bike only produced 24 BHP and I was still to discover what spped it was capable of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Different as it was from most of my previous bikes, I was enjoying the more upright riding position and the quickness of steering as I found it very easy to change direction without much effort. I rode North on the M20, then around the M25 till I came to the A1 which I then rode North on. I stopped for petrol and coffee after a couple of hours and then suitably refreshed I pushed on. The bike could maintain 70 mph on the motorway without much difficulty but I sensed that this was near to the top end of it&amp;rsquo;s performance and I though that it would feel more comfortable around 60 mph. I continued North on the A1 until I came to the A66 at Scotch Corner where I turned left and planned to head for Penrith and then North to the Scottish border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/1-2/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the UK 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain 2019 and Two Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-2019--two-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:40:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/spain-2019--two-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.. the story so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left the city of Reus in in December 2018 for the home of my good friend in Galicia, with only a vague idea about what I wanted to do next. En route I decided to visit the city of Leon, a city that I had always wanted to see but had never actually gotten around to visiting. Leon lived up to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:48:32 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in the city of Opole about a month ago and I must say that of the little of Poland that I have seen, I like this country. In places Poland reminds me of Scotland as it used to be about 40 years ago and in other places it looks just like any other modern European country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:40:22 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it was 1 year ago that I left Scotland behind to make my journey around the world and I arrived in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from my earlier posts, I decided to stay in Spain for 2 years to learn the language as I knew that it would be an invaluable asset on my journey around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what has the 1st year of my journey been like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Break in the Country</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/a-little-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 09:10:42 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/a-little-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is nothing better to lift the spirits than a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, in the middle of July I took the bike out and rode it 1000 km to my friend&amp;rsquo;s house in Galicia. Not a cloud in the sky, 40 degrees and the whole journey I managed to do in (Ahem!) hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At The Zoo</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 19:33:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On arriving in Reus I spent my first uneventful week in the city at a local hotel and I, with some local assistance, attempted to find a suitable place to rent. However, as I was soon to learn, nothing happens quickly in Spain and by the time my check out date was fast approaching I was still no further forward. As the hotel was fully booked for the next week I managed to secure a holiday apartment for two weeks just between the holiday towns of Salou and Cambrils.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks beside the sea what could be better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/at-the-zoo/01-zoo.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unshackled Life</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/an-unshackled-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/an-unshackled-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once I had spent a relaxing night in Santiago de Compostella I boarded a train to the town of Monforte de Lemos which is near to the village where my good friend stays. I had purchased a ticket online (in Spanish) the previous evening and on boarding the train I found that my Spanish was not as good as I had hoped.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the ticket price was 24 Euros for the 70 odd mile journey I had assumed that it was a standard fare but when I took my numbered seat I was quickly ejected from it by an elderly Spanish woman who thrust her ticket under my nose whilst at the same time shouting loudly and pointing at me. Surely the train company had not issued two tickets for the same seat?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over The Finish Line</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 18:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/over-the-finish-line/01-sant.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once my house had eventually been sold it was time for me to leave the UK for good. I hired a car, said my farewells and drove off to England for a few days to do likewise with my friends South of the border. A few days later I was on a plane heading for the next part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part Two</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:25:03 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Northwest of Spain where my friend lives reminds me of Scotland, it is a place full of mountains, tree covered slopes, and deep dark bodies of water. Like Scotland for about two or three months of the year it is cold, it is cloudy, and it rains a lot but this is where the similarities end as for the rest of the year it is sunny and warm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-two/01-gal.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Another Rant</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing--rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 12:56:45 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing--rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have updated this blog, a lot has happened to me since my last post so I shall start where I left off. After leaving my bike at the home of my friend in Galicia I flew back to the UK and arrived a Stanstead airport only to find that my flight to Glasgow was delayed by a couple of hours by snow on the runways, however eventually the plane took off and I was Scotland bound once again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I travelled from Glasgow airport to my home the views of Glasgow from the motorway made my heart sink like the Titanic and like it, I hit rock bottom very quickly. On my way hoe I stopped at a large supermarket to get some provisions and was quickly reminded of the lack of common courtesy displayed by most people who shop there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part One</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:17:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I departed the UK on 14 December 2016 astride my bike sort of as planned (more on this later) and yes it did feel as good as I thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a cold but uneventful 500 mile journey I arrived at Folkestone to drive on to the train that would take me out of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/departing-one/01-bike.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Cluttering of a Life</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 09:11:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/decluttering-of-a-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent dismantling of my present life in preparation for the next part of my life I have found to be an unexpectedly cathartic experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The de-cluttering of a life is something I can now definitely recommend and whether the de-cluttering is solely of unused physical possessions or otherwise is up to you, but it is a process that for me has prompted a realisation that it is perhaps something that I should have done a long time ago. I was surprised at the quantity of items that I possessed for which I had no real use. I may have had a use for them at one time in my life but there they sat in the cupboard, loft, or drawer willing me to hang on to them for just another year, just in case….&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons For Departure...</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/reasons-for-departue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 11:33:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/reasons-for-departue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fully expected that the next post that I made in this blog would be something to do with my bike and how it is now serviced and ready to hurtle off towards the setting sun&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However one of the many reasons as to why I have taken a dislike to this country has just sneaked up and prodded me in the eye. I should know better by now but against my better judgement I had a quick look at the evening news as hosted by the BBC (Biased Broadcasting Corporation) only to be informed that as a result of BREXIT, inflation is on the rise and prices of goods including petrol are expected to rise as a result. I get that, with a weaker pound imported products will cost more, but petrol?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is news to me but according to the upper class twit the BBC produced to explain to the assembled peasantry, the UK apparently buys its oil in US Dollars and since the pound has fallen against the dollar oil is therefore more expensive to buy. Like the argument for imported goods this sounds reasonable unless you are an adult with an IQ over 20, semi-literate, and or live in central Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost at the finishing line for the last time</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another cold winter in Scotland and retirement is almost upon me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/02-snow.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
