<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Costa Rica on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/costa-rica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Costa Rica on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:53:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/costa-rica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/costarica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 14:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/costarica/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Costa Rica are 40 km/h (25 mph) in built up areas, 60 km/h (37 mph) outside built up areas, 80 km/h (50 mph) on dual carriageways and 100 km/h (62 mph) on certain sections of dual carriageways and Toll motorways.&#xA;I All of the road signs for the main roads are White with Black writing.&#xA;The main Costa Rican roads are Highway 2 and 34 in the South of the country below the capitla San Jose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 107 to 10 April 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/107-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/107-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-107&#34;&gt;Day 107&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-107&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Panama city at just after 6 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning on Wednesday 3rd of April and my plan was to get to the city of David which lies about 35 miles West of the main border crossing between Panama and Costa Rica. The bike had just recorded 2,000 miles on the odometer the day before and the ride that day was just under 300 miles. The ride itself was pretty non eventful despite the 14 police speed traps that I passed all the way along Highway 1 during it. The 14 police speed traps that I passed were only the ones on the Eastbound side of Highway 1, there were at least the same number if not more on the Westbound side. I eventually arrived at my destination for the night in the city of David at around 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and I then spent a quite night contemplating whether or not I would be told when I eventually reached the border the following day, if I had the correct documents or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
