<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Switzerland on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/switzerland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Switzerland on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/switzerland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 France, Italy, Switzerland and Lichtenstein to Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Switzerland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 20:45:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/switzerland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Switzerland are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are the A roads, the main non-motorway roads are the N roads, and the smaller main roads just have road names.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways signs are in Blue, the N road signs are in Green, and signs for the smaller roads are white.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 France, Italy, Switzerland, Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things that I have noticed during my riding through France is that the road numbers can suddenly change without warning. For example the D133 that I started on changed mysteriously after about 10 miles and became the D541. Unless one keeps a close eye on this it can get very confusing. Yes, I know a Sat Nav would make this point irrelevant but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I like to travel. Riding further East towards Gap I could see the mountains start to rise in the distance. It had been several years since I had ridden over any Alpine passes and I was looking forward to it but by now the sun was strong, it was very warm, and the scenery forced me to stop, not only to capture its beauty and grandeur but also to pause and soak it all up over a cup of coffee or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
