<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/france/</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 95 to 98 France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-95&#34;&gt;Day 95&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-95&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day it was sunny but cold. I rode for about 10 miles South from Tende on the D6204 and then took the D2204 to go over the Coll De Brouis. The road was fantastic and the views were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/01-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/02-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I stopped in the town of Sospel for coffee and croissants then once heated up by the morning sun I coninued on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/95-98/03-95.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I continued riding on the D2204 and went over the Coll De Braus and Coll De Saint-Jean, again it continued to be a superb biking road with spectacular scenery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 91 to 94 Bosnia, Croatia, Slovenia and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-91&#34;&gt;Day 91&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-91&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I set off North from Sarajevo to Banja Luka which on arrival I found to be a very nondescript city, so deciding not to stop there, I then continued riding and headed West for the Croatian border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/91-94/01-92.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst the scenery in Bosnia was reasonably pleasant, like my time in Serbia, I found very little to hold my attention and like Serbia, it is not a country that I will return to. I crossed the border in to Croatia and I headed West to the coast. I stopped at the first reasonable sized town and I was able to get some Croatian money from an ATM. Luckily I had made better calculations than I had in Serbia so I had no Bosnian cash to try to get rid of, which was fortunate because yet again there were no money exchange facilities at the border crossing. A few weeks before setting off on the trip, I had encountered post in somewhere or other about a guy who ran a small operation hosting bikers in the spare rooms of his house, so having made contact with him I headed for his place. The guy used to run a motorbike shop in England and provided me with very comfortable accommodation for around 20 Euros a night. I stayed for 3 nights to get a bit of a break and to attend to an oil change and some minor tinkering here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 Spain, France, Italy, Austria and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As those who read this blog are aware of my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 Poland, Germany and France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 France, Italy, Switzerland and Lichtenstein to Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28 Spain and Andora to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:49:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-28&#34;&gt;Day 28&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends is always good but leaves a sour taste when it comes time to say goodbye. This occasion was no different. So after a few days rest and relaxation I headed North on the C14 from Reus and made for the Pyrenees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/28/01-28.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riding a bike in the Pyrenees in the summer is a great experience, well surfaced twisty roads, great views and lots of great coffee stops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 17 to 19 France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:13:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-17&#34;&gt;Day 17&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days with a friend in Aix En Provence I said my goodbyes to him and headed for the Spanish border. Leaving Aix En Provence I headed West on the D7N, D572 and D6572 to Montpellier. The journey was pleasant enough in the early morning sun but these roads were too urbanised for my liking so, after circumventing Montpellier I took a short trip West on the A750 motorway until I found the D908 that headed West through the Languedoc National park area. This was a stunning road to ride in the warm early afternoon sunshine. Lots of beautiful scenery, very few cars on the road and the odd picturesque village to stop in and admire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 Poland, Slovakia, Austria and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the actions of an asshole, my time in Krakow was obviously at an end and it was decision time. Either to leave or to assault the asshole. So early one February morning I packed the bike and got ready to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 France, Italy, Switzerland, Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things that I have noticed during my riding through France is that the road numbers can suddenly change without warning. For example the D133 that I started on changed mysteriously after about 10 miles and became the D541. Unless one keeps a close eye on this it can get very confusing. Yes, I know a Sat Nav would make this point irrelevant but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I like to travel. Riding further East towards Gap I could see the mountains start to rise in the distance. It had been several years since I had ridden over any Alpine passes and I was looking forward to it but by now the sun was strong, it was very warm, and the scenery forced me to stop, not only to capture its beauty and grandeur but also to pause and soak it all up over a cup of coffee or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 6 to 8 Spain to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:17:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lounging about in the sun and riding some forest dirt roads in Galicia to reacquaint myself with riding off road it was time to head back to Krakow in Poland where I planned to spend the Winter. After saying my goodbyes in Galicia I set off for the East coast of Spain. I took the N120 from Monforete De lemos to Ponferrada and although this is a fast main road it is quite pleasant to ride on with a bike as it twists and turns as it climbs up the valley of the river Sil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/france/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:38:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in France are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways but the 130 kph limit on the motorways is reduced to 110 kph when it is raining.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are the A roads, the main non-motorway roads are the N roads, and the smaller main roads are the C roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The C roads sometimes change their numbers without warning, so for example lets say that you are on the C413, without warning it suddenly becomes say the the C116 (not a real example) I do not know the reason for this however it is worthwhile keeping an eye on this when using these roads to avoid getting lost or confused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 United Kingdom to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leaving Folkestone I boarded the train that travels under the English channel to France. I have done this a few times before and as usual I met some fellow two wheeled travellers on board. After 20 minutes or so of exchanging stories and thoughts about each other&amp;rsquo;s bikes, I said my farewells and rode South from Calais towards the city of Tours that would be my first stop on my way to Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching. Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule. Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:17:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I departed the UK on 14 December 2016 astride my bike sort of as planned (more on this later) and yes it did feel as good as I thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a cold but uneventful 500 mile journey I arrived at Folkestone to drive on to the train that would take me out of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/departing-one/01-bike.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
