<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>france on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/france/</link>
    <description>Recent content in france on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 August 2021</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about eight months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed.I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/29-31/01-29.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:49:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-28&#34;&gt;Day 28&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends is always good but leaves a sour taste when it comes time to say goodbye. This occasion was no different. So after a few days rest and relaxation I headed North on the C14 from Reus and made for the Pyrenees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/28/01-28.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 24 to 27 July 2020</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/24-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:55:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/24-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-24&#34;&gt;Day 24&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riding along the N125 I passed by Faro and continued untill I had to join the motorway to cross the border in to Spain. I then continued on the A49 from the border, circumventing Seville and headed South on the N4 and A381 till I eventually reached Gibraltar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/24-27/01-24.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 17 to 19 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/17-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:13:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/17-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-17&#34;&gt;Day 17&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days with a friend in Aix En Provence I said my goodbyes to him and headed for the Spanish border. Leaving Aix En Provence I headed West on the D7N, D572 and D6572 to Montpellier. The journey was pleasant enough in the early morning sun but these roads were too urbanised for my liking so, after circumventing Montpellier I took a short trip West on the A750 motorway until I found the D908 that headed West through the Languedoc National park area. This was a stunning road to ride in the warm early afternoon sunshine. Lots of beautiful scenery, very few cars on the road and the odd picturesque village to stop in and admire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/17-19/01-17.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 February 2020</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 September 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 6 to 8 September 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:17:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lounging about in the sun and riding some forest dirt roads in Galicia to reacquaint myself with riding off road it was time to head back to Krakow in Poland where I planned to spend the Winter. After saying my goodbyes in Galicia I set off for the East coast of Spain. I took the N120 from Monforete De lemos to Ponferrada and although this is a fast main road it is quite pleasant to ride on with a bike as it twists and turns as it climbs up the valley of the river Sil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/6-8/01-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in France</title>
      <link>https://example.org/series/themes-guide/france/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:38:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/series/themes-guide/france/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits are as you can see in the picture that I took at the border but the 130 kph limit on the motorways is reduced to 110 kph when it is raining.&#xA;The motorways are the A roads, the main non-motorway roads are the N roads, and the smaller main roads are the C roads.&#xA;The C roads sometimes change their numbers without warning, so for example lets say that you are on the C413, without warning it suddendly becomes say the the C116 (not a real example) I do not know the reason for this however it is worthwhile keeping an eye on this when using these roads to avoid getting lost or confused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 3 to 5 August 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:27:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of my departure I was greeted by a spectacular sunrise and of the Folkstone seafront bathed in early morning sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/3-5/01-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/3-5/02-one.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the UK 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain to Poland 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/spain-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 16:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/spain-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 16th April 2019 I left the home of my friend in Galicia for Poland where I intended to keep myself busy for a few months doing some coaching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usually, when going from A to B I would take the fastest route, however, on this trip I wanted to try some alternatives to the fast but expensive toll motorways that are the norm in most of Europe now and see if I could still maintain some sort of schedule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I started off by crossing Spain, passing the cites of Leon, Burgos and Soria using the extensive network of N class roads that exist as an alternative to the motorways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Departing - Part One</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/departing-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:17:02 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/departing-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I departed the UK on 14 December 2016 astride my bike sort of as planned (more on this later) and yes it did feel as good as I thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a cold but uneventful 500 mile journey I arrived at Folkestone to drive on to the train that would take me out of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/departing-one/01-bike.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost at the finishing line for the last time</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 22:32:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another cold winter in Scotland and retirement is almost upon me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/posts/almost-at-the-finishing-line-for-the-last-time/02-snow.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
