<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hungary on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/hungary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hungary on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/hungary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 79 to 81 August 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-79&#34;&gt;Day 79&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-79&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world is still mad and borders are still shut because of the alleged virus, or wars, or other political nonsense, and all roads East from Central Europe are still closed. So, its on the merry go round once again and back to Spain to visit my friend. However, this time the Balkans are open for business (well apart from Kosovo and Serbia going at it again!) so I decided to take the opportunity to visit these countries whilst I can. Therefore on 15th August 2022 I headed South from Krakow and took the road from there to the Southern Polish city of Bielsko-Biala. I had never actually been here before so this was a perfect time for a visit and I found it to be quite surprising. The town was obviously fortified at some time and the nicer part of the town is to be found within these walls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/79-81/01-79.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 January 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you are all aware my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Hungary</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:15:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/hungary/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Hungary are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&#xA;In Hungary the motorways M roads, the non motorway main roads are just numbered and the smaller roads just have numbers.&#xA;The motorways and the non motorway main roads in Hungary that I rode on were of a good standard, however the smaller roads were not maintained to the same standard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 39 to 42 September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-39&#34;&gt;Day 39&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I head off South from my hotel in Kompachy in the direction of Hungary and at about 12 noon I get to a small border crossing, as expected there is no one on the Slovakian side but I am surprised to see that there are two guards carrying AK47&amp;rsquo;s on the Hungarian side. As I drive towards them I get stopped by the guards and they ask for my passport. They give it back to me and then hand me a form that they have just filled out. As I do not read Hungarian I ask what it is and they tell me it is permission to enter and leave the country so I put it in my passport, thank them and ride on to Budapest where I had booked accommodation for two nights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/39-42/01-39.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
