<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Germany on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/germany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Germany on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/germany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 Poland, Germany and France to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I crossed the border in to the Czech Republic in the rain and rode across to the other side of the county but all the while it continued to rain intermittently. I only stopped for petrol and then moved on trying to get to my destination for that day, the city of Brno as quickly as I could. As I arrived in Brno I got caught in a huge thunderstorm and I got thoroughly soaked before reaching my accommodation for the night. Once sorted out, as the rain had passed I walked in to Brno old town and I found it to be quite pleasant, however, the walk in was not quite as nice. There were lots of people hanging around street corners in large groups, mostly men in the twenties and although they never hassled me, I felt a certain tension in the air. In addition, the streets where these groups were congregating were full of litter and graffiti covered almost every wall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 to 31 France, Italy, Switzerland and Lichtenstein to Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 10:31:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/29-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-29&#34;&gt;Day 29&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long night of drinking, smoking cigars and chatting I eventually left the home of my friend at at around noon the following day. My plan was to try to get up the highest unpaved road in Europe which is the Coll Du Jandre. However, my over indulgence the previous night had left me short of time so I headed in the general direction of Briancon to see where I ended up at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:11:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Germany are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are are called Autobahns and are just numbered. They are also toll free. The non-motorway main roads are also just numbered, and the smaller roads just have road names.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain parts of the Autobahns have no speed limit and when driving on these roads it is very important to take great care when overtaking a slower moving vehicle as some other vehicle may be approaching you at extremely high speed. The best advice that I can give is once you decide to overtake make sure nothing is coming up fast behind you and then once you have made your ovetake get back in to the inside lane as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 9 to 12 France, Italy, Switzerland, Germany and Czech Republic to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 14:34:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-9&#34;&gt;Day 9&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off along the D133 in the direction of Gap and at last the sun was out, it was warm and the bike was running well. En route to Gap I passed through the town of Grignan which had a large fortress type building dominating the skyline above the town and so I stopped to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/9-12/10-six.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things that I have noticed during my riding through France is that the road numbers can suddenly change without warning. For example the D133 that I started on changed mysteriously after about 10 miles and became the D541. Unless one keeps a close eye on this it can get very confusing. Yes, I know a Sat Nav would make this point irrelevant but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I like to travel. Riding further East towards Gap I could see the mountains start to rise in the distance. It had been several years since I had ridden over any Alpine passes and I was looking forward to it but by now the sun was strong, it was very warm, and the scenery forced me to stop, not only to capture its beauty and grandeur but also to pause and soak it all up over a cup of coffee or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
