<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>germany on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/germany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in germany on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/tags/germany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 70 to 73 August 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:52:27 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/70-73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-70&#34;&gt;Day 70&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-70&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The madness is still with us and four years after leaving the UK on my RTW trip and it is still disrupting my travel plans, borders are still closed or heavily restricted. Some countries are demanding that people who want to enter their country must have taken the experimental gene therapy injection or they must get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo; or both. I had now been in Krakow for about 8 months and nothing has changed to the East, all roads are still closed. I needed to get on the bike and start travelling again, if only to obtain a bit of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 32 to 33 August 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:49 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/32-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-32&#34;&gt;Day 32&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I departed from the Gasthof the weather was not great and it started to rain a little. Once again, I stayed off the motorways as much as possible but progress was slow and occasionally to make up some time I was forced to use the Autobahn. As a result these was little to see and even less reason to stop and photograph anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:11:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/germany/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Germany are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&#xA;The motorways are are called Autobahns and are just numbered. They are also toll free. The non-motorway main roads are also just numbered, and the smaller roads just have road names.&#xA;Certain parts of the Autobahns have no speed limit and when driving on these roads it is very important to take great care when overtaking a slower moving vehicle as some other vehicle may be approaching you at extremely high speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poland to the UK 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:52 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/poland-uk-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always known that my Kawasaki ZZR1200 would not be a suitable bike to use on an RTW trip and although I had planned to change it, I had not really decided on what bike that should be nor when I should change it, so in July 2019 I made the decision that the time was now right to change my bike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As during my RTW trip I necessarily had planned to cover a lot of miles, the fuel that I would use would be a significant part of my daily expenditure, therefore low fuel consumption would be a very important factor in whatever bike that I chose. Ease of maintenance and repair were the next most important factors on my list of requirements, closely followed by being a bike light enough for me to pick up unassisted. After doing a lot of research and reading a lot of reviews I decided that the Royal Enfield Himalayan was the one that I though most suited my needs as an RTW bike. So in August 2019 I decided to return to the UK and to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
