<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serbia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/serbia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serbia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 08:13:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/serbia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Serbia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 08:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Serbia are 60 km/h (38 mph) in built up areas, 100 km/h (62 mph) outside built up areas, and 120 km/h (74 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Serbia the motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter A, the non motorway main roads are numbered, the smaller roads just have the names of the town that they lead to on the signs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Serbian motorways and the non motorway main roads that I rode on are of a good standard, the condition of the smaller roads are generally good but there is always the odd exception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 82 to 84 Hungary and Serbia to North Macedonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-82&#34;&gt;Day 82&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-82&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miskloc is a place that I had again passed by whilst transiting through Hungary but I had never actually stopped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/82-84/01-82.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is quite a well spread out city that is much longer East to West that in its from North to South. The city does not have a central square and this seems to be a thing in Slovakia, Hungary and other countries to the South of Europe, instead it has an elongated main street on which most of the shops, bars, and cafes are located. From my experiences it seems to me that central squares seem to be more prevalent in Northern European countries for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
