<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bulgaria on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bulgaria/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bulgaria on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bulgaria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 65 to 67 November 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-65&#34;&gt;Day 65&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-65&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for leaving Turkey was because all of the land routes to the East from Turkey were closed and because of this I had to decide where to go for the winter. Staying in Turkey was an option but having a 90 day limit to my stay would have meant having to leave Turkey at the end of January to go back a European country. Another factor for consideration was the potential for the alleged virus to affect border crossings at the end of January in to February. As the borders were still open at that time I decided that it would be better to make that journey in early November rather than at the beginning of February. I left Kırklareli early the next day and headed for the Bulgarian border. On approaching the border the road rose sharply and in the shaded parts, the road was covered in frost. A few minutes at the border and I was once again in Bulgaria. I rode along the coast past Burgas and Varna, I only stopped for fuel and coffee as it was not warming up and it had become overcast. I was at the Romanian border by late afternoon and once through I headed for the unremarkable city of Constanta where I spent the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 46 September 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:57:01 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-45&#34;&gt;Day 45&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-45&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 days off the bike I needed to get going again so I left Sofia in the pouring rain and headed South East in the direction of Plovdiv. My reasons for visiting Plovdiv were twofold, firstly I had read that this city was the oldest continually inhabited city in Europe and secondly, as I wanted to visit Greece, I needed to get tested for the alleged virus and a hospital in Plovdiv provided this service. I booked in to a modern hotel a short walk from the old town for 4 nights at about 30 Euros per night. While I waited on being tested I explored the city and found that the city had a lot of excavated Roman architecture still visible in the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/45-46/01-45.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 43 to 44 September 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-43&#34;&gt;Day 43&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-43&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day when I arrived at the Bulgarian border it was pretty quiet and there were just a couple of cars in the queue in front of me but then I encountered one of the most common road defects that Central and East Europe has to offer, &amp;ldquo;Tramlines&amp;rdquo;. These are the large longitudinal indentations left in the road surface by the repeated driving on hot, soft, tarmac by very heavy lorries. Unfortunately, they change the camber of the road and whilst waiting in line to be seen by the Romanian authorities and sitting astride my bike in one of these &amp;ldquo;tramlines&amp;rdquo;, I dropped my passport. My passport landed on the road to the right of the bike just out of my reach, so I put the bike of the side stand and dismounted to retrieve it. As I picked it up I heard the sickening crunch of my bike hitting the road. A combination of the bike sitting in the &amp;ldquo;tramline&amp;rdquo;, the side stand resting on an adverse camber, and a strong gust of wind caused the bike to fall over, bending the brake lever in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, a few minutes later, passport and bike documents checked, I was in Bulgaria and changing my Romanian currency for Bulgarian currency. I stopped and grabbed a coffee and a cigar and as I sat drinking my coffee I realised that I was fatigued and needed to take a few day off from riding the bike. So I made a decision then and there to find some place relatively close to the border and take a break from riding for a few days. I found a small studio flat overlooking the Black sea just North of the city of Varna for about 14 Euros per night, so I decided to rest there for a while. This was the view from my balcony and of the nearby beach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/01-43.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
