<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albania on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/albania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albania on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 15:38:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/albania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Albania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/albaina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 15:38:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/albaina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Albania are 40 km/h (25 mph) within built-up areas, 80 km/h (50 mph) outside built-up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) on Dual Carriageways, and 110 km/h (68 mph) on Motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Albania the motorways are numbered and prefixed with the letter A, the non motorway main roads are numbered and prefixed with the letters SH, the smaller roads just have the names of the town that they lead to on the signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 88 to 90 Albainia and Montenegro to Bosnia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-88&#34;&gt;Day 88&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-88&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once packed and on the road early the next morning, I headed in land for a bit before the road headed for the coast again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/01-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/02-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/03-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took the coastal road up to Vlore and this was again a stunning road to ride along. This road rose and fell continually and at one point from one decent vantage point I photographed Vlore from the roadside.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/04-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/88-90/05-88.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North of Vlore I followed the coast until I got to Tirana the capital city of Albania. This route in this part of the country I would not recommend as the roads were much busier and the countryside was pretty flat. In addition, most of the buildings that could be seen from the road were partly finished and partly a construction site. When I got to Tirana I booked a &amp;ldquo;Communist Style&amp;rdquo; room for about 20 Euros, however the name was merely a marketing ploy to attract gullible tourists (like myself on this occasion) to pay for an unrenovated room stuffed with old 1970&amp;rsquo;s furniture. To be fair it did however have some reproduction communist style electrical appliances so I suppose it fulfilled the description to some degree. Tirana was not what I had expected and much of the city was very modern. The main focal point of the city was a massive square where the opera is situated but there was little around it in the way of bars, cafes, or restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 85 to 87 North Macedonia to Albania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-85&#34;&gt;Day 85&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-85&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, after breakfast I headed West through the mountains in the direction of the Albanian border crossing at Lake Ohrid, however, as I was nearing the border I saw the dark clouds massing and just managed to get in to a petrol station before an enormous thunderstorm rolled in keeping me drinking coffee for nearly 2 hours until it passed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/85-87/01-85.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I eventually crossed the Albanian border it was late in the afternoon so my first task was to get a SIM card and cash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
