<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovakia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/slovakia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovakia on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/slovakia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 79 to 81 Poland and Slovakia to Hungary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/79-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/79-81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-79&#34;&gt;Day 79&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-79&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world is still mad and borders are still shut because of the alleged virus, or wars, or other political nonsense, and all roads East from Central Europe are still closed. So, its on the merry go round once again and back to Spain to visit my friend. However, this time the Balkans are open for business (well apart from Kosovo and Serbia going at it again!) so I decided to take the opportunity to visit these countries whilst I can. Therefore on 15th August 2022 I headed South from Krakow and took the road from there to the Southern Polish city of Bielsko-Biala. I had never actually been here before so this was a perfect time for a visit and I found it to be quite surprising. The town was obviously fortified at some time and the nicer part of the town is to be found within these walls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 Spain, France, Italy, Austria and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As those who read this blog are aware of my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 Romania, Hungary and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 39 to 42 Slovakia and Hungary to Romanaia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-39&#34;&gt;Day 39&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I head off South from my hotel in Kompachy in the direction of Hungary and at about 12 noon I get to a small border crossing, as expected there is no one on the Slovakian side but I am surprised to see that there are two guards carrying AK47&amp;rsquo;s on the Hungarian side. As I drive towards them I get stopped by the guards and they ask for my passport. They give it back to me and then hand me a form that they have just filled out. As I do not read Hungarian I ask what it is and they tell me it is permission to enter and leave the country so I put it in my passport, thank them and ride on to Budapest where I had booked accommodation for two nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 34 to 38 Poland, Lithuania and Ukrainian Border to Slovakia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 18:39:41 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-34&#34;&gt;Day 34&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-34&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I had finished with my coaching I resumed my travels and I headed North to Warsaw. I stayed in a small hotel on the edge of Warsaw for under 30 Euros and I was able to take the metro in to the city centre which I walked about in for a while, I also found that the old town was somewhat touristy but nonetheless quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/01-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/02-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/34-38/03-34.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-35&#34;&gt;Day 35&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-35&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning I set off to do another favour for another friend. I had been told by my fiend that her father had escaped Poland as a boy in the aftermath of WW2 and had then settled in the USA. She had asked me to swing by the village that her father had been born in near to Byzgoszcz and take some photographs for her. Once this mission had been accomplished I headed North to Gdansk where I spent the night in a cheery hostel full of odd characters for under 20 Euros.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Slovakia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 12:32:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Slovakia are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are numbered. All of the motorways are toll roads. The main non-motorway roads are also just numbered, and the smaller main roads are also just numbered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways signs have a Blue background, the main road signs have a Green background, signs for the smaller roads are on a Dark Blue background.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 Poland, Slovakia, Austria and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the actions of an asshole, my time in Krakow was obviously at an end and it was decision time. Either to leave or to assault the asshole. So early one February morning I packed the bike and got ready to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
