<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central America on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/categories/central-america/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Central America on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/categories/central-america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 123 to 124 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-123&#34;&gt;Day 123&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-123&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my accommodation in Coban at just after 8 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and set off for the city of Huehuetenango which I had decided to ride to that day. Google maps showed that Huehuetenango was just over 120 miles away but the time to do it was show as nearly 5 hours so I knew to expect some slow going in parts of my journey for the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as I left Coban I saw a really nice roadside restaurant so I pulled in for coffee and breakfast, steak with scrambled eggs for 35 Quetzals (4.50 US Dollars)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/123-124/01-123.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Honduras</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/honduras/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 12:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/honduras/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Honduras are 40 km/h (25 mph) or 60 km/h (37 mph) in built up areas, outside built up areas all roads are limited to 80 km/h (50 mph)&#xA;All of the road signs for the main roads are Green with White writing and the local roads are White with Black writing.&#xA;The main roads in Honduras are either tarmac or concrete and they are all generally good and reasonably well maintained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 121 to 122 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-121&#34;&gt;Day 121&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-121&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was another hot day in Honduras, when I set off from Puerto Cortes at 7 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was already displaying 33 degrees Celsius on my bike. I headed for the Guatemalan border that was about an hour away and as the road passed close to the coast I stopped to take a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/121-122/01-121.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Nicaragua</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/nicaragua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/nicaragua/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Nicaragua are 40 km/h (25 mph) or 60 km/h (37 mph) in built up areas, outside built up areas all roads are limited to 80 km/h (50 mph)&#xA;All of the road signs for the main roads are Green with White writing and the local roads are White with Black writing.&#xA;The main roads in Nicaragua are either tarmac or concrete and they are all generally very good and well maintained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 119 to 120 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-119&#34;&gt;Day 119&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-119&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my stay in Managua I managed to obtain 2 new electrical relays for the bike which should now hopefully put an end to the starting issue I experienced a few days earlier. One other thing that I needed to attend to was that after my escapades with the punctures, when the bike was in the back of the truck full of sand, somehow or other a load of sand had gotten inside of my petrol tank via the filler cap. Thankfully it was in the overflow drain and not actually inside the tank with the petrol.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/119-120/01-120.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 117 to 118 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-117&#34;&gt;Day 117&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-117&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So after another day in puncture city I was ready to continue my journey. I set off at 8 am and I was more than a little relieved that everything on the bike seemed to be working normally but it was not long until I reached the roadworks and the stretches of gravel roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/117-118/01-117.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/costarica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/costarica/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Costa Rica are 40 km/h (25 mph) in built up areas, 60 km/h (37 mph) outside built up areas, 80 km/h (50 mph) on dual carriageways and the toll roads.&#xA;All of the road signs for the main roads are Green with White writing and the local roads are White with Black writing.&#xA;The main Costa Rican roads are Highway 2 and 34 in the South of the country below the capital San Jose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 116 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-116&#34;&gt;Day 116&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-116&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up early and got ready to head off before 7 am as I knew that I had to contend with the unfinished road and the stone chip and gravel sections on my return from the coast. I left my hotel but as I was just about at the edge of town I got another puncture in my back tyre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/116/01-116.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 114 to 115 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-114&#34;&gt;Day 114&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-114&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I left Juigalpa it was a little overcast and just North of the town I stopped to take a photo of the mountains in the distance to the East.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/114-115/01-114.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 112 to 113 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-112&#34;&gt;Day 112&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-112&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst in San Marcos I stayed at a nice hotel which was a little expensive at $40 per night although breakfast was included in that price. However nice it was in San Marcos, I tend to get restless when I am off the bike for too long so on Monday 15th April I set off for the capital city, San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/112-113/01-112.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 110 to 111 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-110&#34;&gt;Day 110&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-110&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent 3 nights at my accommodation in San Isidro and to be honest there was not much to do in the city and whilst I was there the weather started to turn showery which discouraged me from exploring further on the bike. I used my time to catch up on the usual housekeeping stuff like emails etc. and when eventually it was time to leave I have to say that I was glad to move on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left San Isidro in the direction of San Jose (the capital city of Costa Rica) and immediately the road started to climb, and climb. In total the road climbed up in to the mountains for about 30 miles before it levelled off a bit and by this time I was high enough in the mountains to be above some clouds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/110--111/02-110.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 107 to 109 April 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/107-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/107-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-107&#34;&gt;Day 107&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-107&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Panama city at just after 6 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning on Wednesday 3rd of April and my plan was to get to the city of David which lies about 35 miles West of the main border crossing between Panama and Costa Rica. The bike had just recorded 2,000 miles on the odometer the day before and the ride that day was just under 300 miles. The ride itself was pretty non eventful despite the 14 police speed traps that I passed all the way along Highway 1 during it. The 14 police speed traps that I passed were only the ones on the Westbound side of Highway 1, there were at least the same number if not more on the Eastbound side. I eventually arrived at my destination for the night in the city of David at around 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and I then spent a quite night contemplating whether or not I would be told when I eventually reached the border the following day, if I had the correct documents or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Down</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/seven-years-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/seven-years-down/</guid>
      <description>Seven Years DownIt is now April 2024 and it has been 7 years since I left the UK to commence what I thought would be an around the world trip on my bike and my goodness how the world has changed!&#xA;At the beginning of 2020 the world descended in to insanity and madness and, to me at least, it seems that no meaningful recovery to sanity has yet been achieved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Panama</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/panama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 14:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/series/themes-guide/panama/</guid>
      <description>The speed limits in Panama are 40 km/h (25 mph) in built up areas, 60 km/h (37 mph) outside built up areas, 80 km/h (50 mph) on dual carriageways and 100 km/h (62 mph) on certain sections of dual carriageways and Toll motorways.&#xA;In Panama there are only 3 Toll motorways. They are all in and around Panama city. The first 2 are the South Corridor and the North Corridor which form a ring road around Panama city.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 104 to 106 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/104-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/104-106/</guid>
      <description>Day 104On leaving my jungle accommodation I had a short 20 or so mile ride to the border. On the way back to the main road I stopped at a bridge over the river and took a couple of photos of the crossing.&#xA;As I got near to the border I pulled in to a petrol station to refuel as I had heard that the price of petrol in Costa Rica is much more expensive that it is in Panama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 103 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/103/</guid>
      <description>Day 103The road to Boquette ends shortly after the Northern edge of the town and it is in effect a dead end, so to leave it there is no alternative but to retrace your steps back down Highway 41 in the direction of the city of David. So setting off South out of Boquette my plan was to head up to the Caribbean side of Panama and cross the border in to Costa Rica at the town of Guabito.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 101 to 103 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/101-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/101-102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-101&#34;&gt;Day 101&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-101&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a few days in Las Tablas I set off South on Highway 2 to explore the peninsula. I rode along the South coast of the peninsula and then I headed North to Macaracas and then on to Highway 50 where I eventually re-joined the main road, Highway 1. To be honest there was very little of interest to see in the peninsula except for signs of land being cleared for future developments, presumably to exploit the Southern coastline for tourists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I then headed West for Santiago where I spent the night at a hotel by the side of the main road about 10 miles East of the city for about $30. It was a nice enough place but there was nothing near to the hotel which had no restaurant. Another downside to this hotel was that during the night there was a lot of noise and serious vibrations from the passing lorries that thundered along taking advantage of the deserted road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 99 to 100 February 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/99-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/99-100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-99&#34;&gt;Day 99&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-99&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 11 February I headed off from the hotel in Panama city where I had been staying, North in the direction of Colon. In an earlier post I had visited Colon and found it not to my liking however, I was following a recommendation that I had received to visit the beaches to the East of the city. So as I approached the city I took a small road along the Caribbean coast to the East and headed for the town of Portobello where I had booked in to a hostel for 4 nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 2024 Out and About in Panama</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rode the bike to the City of Colon on the Caribbean side of the isthmus of Panama to get some miles done to help the engine break in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/out-and-about/01-ri.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December 2023 Part Two</title>
      <link>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:36:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;The Americas - Getting Started&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#the-americas---getting-started&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am now in Panama and I am preparing to continue my RTW trip from here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.offthehamsterwheel.co.uk/posts/part-two/01-ct.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have bought a new Himalayan from the local dealer here and as it only had 2 kilometres on the clock, I had to begin the process of breaking the engine in. So in real terms that means keeping the engine speeds below 3,000 RPM for the first 300 miles (500 km) which translates in to a top speed of 40 mph (60 kph)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
