<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austria on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/austria/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Austria on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/austria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 74 to 78 Spain, France, Italy, Austria and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/74-78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-74&#34;&gt;Day 74&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-74&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As those who read this blog are aware of my travels, like those of many others, have been restricted by measures brought in by Governments around the world. Until now such measures have had little direct impact on my travels other than not being able to head East out of Europe. On this journey these measures directly impacted me and my ability to travel as I usually do. The reason that I am writing about this is that as a consequence I made certain choices about my journey that I would perhaps not otherwise have made. I want to make it clear that I am not writing about this to start a discussion about these matters as I do not think that this is an appropriate place to do so, but solely to tell my story about what happened on my trip and why I made certain choices about my travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 13 to 16 Poland, Slovakia, Austria and Italy to France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:11:56 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/13-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-13&#34;&gt;Day 13&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just know that your plans will not work out and despite your best efforts everything turns to shit. In most cases, the reason for your plans going sideways is usually the actions of another person, and in my case things were no different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asshole is an asshole and there is just no other way to say it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the actions of an asshole, my time in Krakow was obviously at an end and it was decision time. Either to leave or to assault the asshole. So early one February morning I packed the bike and got ready to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
