<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>South America on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/south-america/</link>
    <description>Recent content in South America on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/south-america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 145 to 146 Quito to Huaquillas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-145&#34;&gt;Day 145&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-145&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left Quito early and it was cold. The road out of the city climbed and climbed and at one point I got a break in the clouds from where I could take a photo of the city below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/145-146/01-145.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However just after I set off again I was back in to the clouds and climbing again. Once on the descent I encountered a road accident in the fast lane where a car had stuffed itself under the back of a bus in the heavy fog. The diesel tank of the bus had ruptured and it was running down the road but luckily for me the road was so steep that it all ran straight downhill in the outside lane and it did not flow across the road in to the inside lane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 144 Colombia to Ecuador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-144&#34;&gt;Day 144&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-144&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was overcast when I left my hotel in San Juan and headed for the border. I arrived there at about half past eight in the morning and it was busy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/144/13-144.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I parked the bike outside the immigration and cusoms building and I was immediately approached by a guy who wanted to change my Colombian pesos for USD which they use in Ecuador. The guy gave me a competetive rate so I changed what I had and then he offered to watch my bike for me whilst I went to immigration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 142 to 143 Neiva to San Juan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/142-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/142-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-142&#34;&gt;Day 142&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-142&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning as I prepared to leave my hotel it was overcast and the rain had just stopped. The previous evening I had looked at the map and I had decided to return to route 43 on which I would head South on but for some unknown reason I forgot about that and I headed South out of Neiva on route 45. The early moring air was quite cool and the further South I went the cooler it got and then it started to rain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 140 to 141 Santa Marta to Neiva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/140-141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/140-141/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-140&#34;&gt;Day 140&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-140&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the moring of the 26th of December I said my farewells to my good friends Eric, Alison, and an Italian guy called Alessandro with whom I had become friends whilst we were both staying at the hostel. Alessandro had just bought himself a new Suzuki GN125F and he was in the process of running it in before heading South on a journey similar to mine. I then set off to start the biggest adventure of my life so far, to ride to my bike all the way to town of Ushuaia in the Tierra Del Fuego province of Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/santa-marta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/santa-marta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-santa-marta&#34;&gt;Impressions of Santa Marta&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-santa-marta&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I write this post I am currently in Santa Marta but by the time that it comes for me to leave I will have stayed in the city for about three weeks and so far I have really enjoyed my time here. I am planning to spend Christmas day in Santa Matra with two good friends whom I recently met in Panama city. My friends Eric and Allison are originally from Scotland but they emigrated to Canada over twenty years ago and meeting them in Panama was the first time that I had actually seen them since they left Scotland all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 139 La Guajira Desert to Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/139/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/139/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-139&#34;&gt;Day 139&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-139&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I got ready to leave Riohacha at about nine o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning it was a little bit cloudy which I was glad of as it was not as hot as it had been the previous morning. I quickly refuelled the bike and then I rode out of the town for a few miles on the main road North before turning on to the road that would eventually take me to the coastal town of Manaure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 138 Cartagena to Riohacha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/138/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-138&#34;&gt;Day 138&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-138&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was glad that it was eventually time to leave Cartagena and although it was Saurday morning I set off early in order to avoid any traffic only to find that there was some sort of cycle race taking place and the road out of the city was full of cyclists who were wandering all over the road.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I had negoitated my way out of the city without mowing down any of the cyclists that were making sudden and unannounced U turns in front of me, I headed for the city of Baranquilla which was about fifty miles further up the coast to the North. The road from Cartagena to Baranquilla was not particularly interesting apart from having to ride over a large but newish suspension bridge that spanned a wide river as I left Cartagena.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cartagena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cartagena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-cartagena&#34;&gt;Impressions of Cartagena&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-cartagena&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my way in to Cartagena I had to ride through the city at around four o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon and as one can imagine it was complete chaos. Where I was staying was close to the old fortress that is a major landmark and tourist attraction for the city but this area is also at the Northernmost edge of the city so I had to ride through the the entire length of city to get to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 136 to 137 Medellin to Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/136-137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-136&#34;&gt;Day 136&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-136&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set off from Medellin at around seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, it was overcast and it looked as if it was about to rain but I had high hopes of staying dry once I had gotten out of the city and I was heading in the direcection of the Caribbean coast. I had a brief entanglement with the morning rush hour traffic but as I was heading out of the city rather than in to it I managed to avoid the worst of the traffic chaos. I eventually found the correct road, the Autopista al Mar 1, and I headed up in to the mountains to the North of the city and within a half an hour I was clear of Medellin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medellin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/medellin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/medellin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-medellin&#34;&gt;Impressions of Medellin&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-medellin&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hotel in Medellin was situated in a good location about a ten minute walk North of the main train station. The city has an elevated metro system and a tram system together with lots of local buses. The two main metro lines and tram system lines converge at the San Antonio metro station which was about a five minute walk from where I was staying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought a card for the transport systems from the kiosk in the San Antonio metro station and it cost me about 3 USD including four journeys. The card that I bought allowed me use the metro, the tram, the buses, and the cable car system which I presumed was designed to take local residents up the steep slopes of the surrounding mountains on which lots of housing could be seen on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 134 to 135 Bogota to Medellin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/134-135/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/134-135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-134&#34;&gt;Day 134&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-134&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left my hotel in Bogota at around seven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, it was sunny and quite cool but at least it was not raining. I had just about reached the West side of the city when the traffic ground to a halt. For the next hour and a half I slowly filtered throught the stationary traffic trying to get on to the road to Medellin. Beacuse of the huge number of people in Colombia that use bikes as their everyday transport, even the filtering bikes were backed up for miles. Along with the other bikers I swapped lanes trying to get in to one that had a clear gap but every time one opened up all of the other bikers quickly filled up all of the available space between the lanes of stationry cars, buses, and lorries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bogota</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bogota/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bogota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-of-bogota&#34;&gt;Impressions of Bogota&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#impressions-of-bogota&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hotel in Bogota was situated in a good location near to the popular tourist neighbourhood of La Candelaria and close to a major pedestrian street full of shops and bars. This side of Bogota is bordered by some hills on top of which sits the church of Monserrate which is another favourite tourist spot. I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do the tourist bit but since I was in the city for a few days I decided to venture up to the top using the fenicular railway. However once I got to the base of the hill there were large queues of peole wating to go up so that put paid to me going up as I hate queing for such things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;Arrving in South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#arrving-in-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the bike had been left at the airport and after a night in Panama city on the beer and cigars with my friends, I made my way to the airport to catch my flight to Bogota. The flight was sheduled to leave at 3:25 pm and to arrive in Bogota at 5:10 pm. I boarded the plane and the 3:25 pm departure time came and went with all of us still sitting in the plane on the airport standing waiting to taxi. The plane started moving around 3:40 pm and the plane began taxiing, and taxiing, and taxiing. I thought that it was going all of the way in to Panama city. Eventually at 4:05 pm the plane took off. Now either the plane was much faster than usual or the hanging around on the plane at the airport in Panama is included in the flight time because after an uneventful flight it landed at Bogota at the scheduled arrival time of 5:10 pm. Very strange!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;Getting Ready For South America&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#getting-ready-for-south-america&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the time had come for me to stop loitering about Panama City like a bad smell and get myself and the bike to Colombia to start the South American part of my trip. It is now turning Summer in South America and I wanted to reach Tierra Del Fuego during the good weather window between the start of January and the end of March so it was time to get my arse in gear and get things moving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
