<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portugal on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/portugal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portugal on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 11:05:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/portugal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Portugal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 11:05:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/portugal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Portugal are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 120 km/h (78 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like Spain, the motorways are the A roads, the main non-motorway roads are the N roads, but in Portugal the smaller main roads are the M roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motorways are all of a high standard but some are toll roads and some are not. Some of the toll motorways are of the automatic type and this means that you need to register your vehicle on the appropriate website before making your journey, however some have manual tolls and you can just pay at the toll booths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 24 to 27 Portugal to Spain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:55:12 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-24&#34;&gt;Day 24&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After saying my goodbyes to my friends in Alvor I headed West. Riding along the N125 I passed by Faro and continued until I had to join the motorway to cross the border in to Spain. I then continued on the A49 from the border, circumventing Seville and headed South on the N4 and A381 till I eventually reached Gibraltar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/24-27/01-24.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once there I was disappointed as it was nothing like I had expected it to be and the only positive thing that I have to say about Gibraltar was the price of petrol at only 85 cents per litre. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what I was expecting but it seemed very cluttered, almost industrial in nature, so after a quick circuit it was back across the border and back in to Spain where I found a reasonable motel room for under 25 Euros for the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bike Repairs in Portugal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rocker-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 09:16:36 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rocker-cover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;Leaky Rocker Cover&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#leaky-rocker-cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Alvor at the home of my friend and her husband to spend a few days catching up but the bike had developed a slight oil leak from the rocker/cylinder head cover so I spent the next few days attending to that. The removal was pretty straightforward except for the removal of the camshaft end plate, it was stuck solid with gasket sealant. However, once I finally got if off without damaging it, the removal of the old gasket sealant was pretty straightforward. I used ethanol and a small plastic scourer, the type they sell in multi-packs in every supermarket, and with a bit of time and effort both mating surfaces were cleaned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/rocker-cover/01-jane.jpg&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 20 to 23 Spain to Portugal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 11:29:33 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-20&#34;&gt;Day 20&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well with the best of intentions I arrived at my friends house in Galicia in late February 2020. Then suddenly, like almost every other place on the plant, I was unable to travel due to the alleged pandemic. As news of borders re-opening and travel being permitted once again started to circulate, I got the bike ready to move. I fitted new Mitas E-07 tires, carried out an oil and filter change, the engine tappets and the wheel spokes were adjusted as required, a new touring seat purchased and fitted, the brake fluid was changed and both calipers cleaned and greased. I got a set of custom made side plates to stop my soft throwover panniers tucking in on the back wheel and because of the broken rear indicator stem that I picked up when an old man in a car side swiped me in Italy the previous year, I got indicator protectors built in to the plates and once these were fitted the bike was good to go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
