<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Romania on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/romania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Romania on OFF THE HAMSTER WHEEL</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/romania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Days 68 to 69 Romania, Hungary and Slovakia to Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:19:19 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/68-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-68&#34;&gt;Day 68&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-68&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had spent the night in the town of Satu Mare close to the border crossing with Hungary. I had read that Hungary was open for transit only and that Slovakia were testing people at the border for the alleged virus. I expected to encounter lots of ongoing insane procedures and laws being implemented by border officials and the possibility of being turned away at either or both of the borders. The next morning to compound my potential issues it was cold and raining heavily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 65 to 67 Turkey, Bulgaria and Moldovian Border to Romania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:28:16 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/65-67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-65&#34;&gt;Day 65&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-65&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for leaving Turkey was because all of the land routes to the East from Turkey were closed and because of this I had to decide where to go for the winter. Staying in Turkey was an option but having a 90 day limit to my stay would have meant having to leave Turkey at the end of January to go back a European country. Another factor for consideration was the potential for the alleged virus to affect border crossings at the end of January in to February. As the borders were still open at that time I decided that it would be better to make that journey in early November rather than at the beginning of February. I left Kırklareli early the next day and headed for the Bulgarian border. On approaching the border the road rose sharply and in the shaded parts, the road was covered in frost. A few minutes at the border and I was once again in Bulgaria. I rode along the coast past Burgas and Varna, I only stopped for fuel and coffee as it was not warming up and it had become overcast. I was at the Romanian border by late afternoon and once through I headed for the unremarkable city of Constanta where I spent the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biking in Romania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/romaina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 19:02:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/series/themes-guide/romaina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The speed limits in Romania are 50 km/h (50 mph) in built up areas, 90 km/h (56 mph) outside built up areas, and 130 km/h (86 mph) on motorways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Romania the motorways A roads, the non motorway main roads are just numbered and the smaller roads just have numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I never rode on the motorways and the non motorway main roads in Romania that I rode on are of a good standard. The smaller roads were not maintained to the same standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 43 to 44 Romanaia to Bulgaria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/43-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-43&#34;&gt;Day 43&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-43&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day when I arrived at the Bulgarian border it was pretty quiet and there were just a couple of cars in the queue in front of me but then I encountered one of the most common road defects that Central and East Europe has to offer, &amp;ldquo;Tramlines&amp;rdquo;. These are the large longitudinal indentations left in the road surface by the repeated driving on hot, soft, tarmac by very heavy lorries. Unfortunately, they change the camber of the road and whilst waiting in line to be seen by the Romanian authorities and sitting astride my bike in one of these &amp;ldquo;tramlines&amp;rdquo;, I dropped my passport. My passport landed on the road to the right of the bike just out of my reach, so I put the bike of the side stand and dismounted to retrieve it. As I picked it up I heard the sickening crunch of my bike hitting the road. A combination of the bike sitting in the &amp;ldquo;tramline&amp;rdquo;, the side stand resting on an adverse camber, and a strong gust of wind caused the bike to fall over, bending the brake lever in the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days 39 to 42 Slovakia and Hungary to Romanaia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:27:51 -0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/39-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-39&#34;&gt;Day 39&lt;a class=&#34;anchorjs-link&#34; href=&#34;#day-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day I head off South from my hotel in Kompachy in the direction of Hungary and at about 12 noon I get to a small border crossing, as expected there is no one on the Slovakian side but I am surprised to see that there are two guards carrying AK47&amp;rsquo;s on the Hungarian side. As I drive towards them I get stopped by the guards and they ask for my passport. They give it back to me and then hand me a form that they have just filled out. As I do not read Hungarian I ask what it is and they tell me it is permission to enter and leave the country so I put it in my passport, thank them and ride on to Budapest where I had booked accommodation for two nights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
